He said four minutes precisely.
Il a dit quatre minutes pile.
Quickly.
Vite.
Two perfect eggs this time, no?
Sont-ils parfaits cette fois ?
Maybe.
Peut-ךtre.
I blame the chicken.
C'est la faute de la poule.
Why do hens lay eggs of different sizes?
Pourquoi pondre des ufs de taille inיgale ?
It's not you, mon ami.
Ce n'est pas ta faute, mon ami.
These are two perfectly good oeufs.
Ces ufs sont tout א fait convenables.
Mr. Poirot...
M. Poirot...
I've got three religions bent on riot.
J'ai trois religions au bord de l'יmeute.
If you're going to perform one of your miracles,
Si vous nous rיservez un de vos miracles,
the time is now.
c'est le moment.
Have the eggs. Allons-y!
Les ufs sont pour toi. Allons-y !
Poirot!
Poirot !
Sorry for the, um...
Pardon pour le...
It is not the, uh...
Ce n'est pas le...
It is the imbalance of the...
C'est le dיsיquilibre du...
Right.
Je vois.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Excusez-moi. Libיrez le chemin.
Please call for the accused.
Faites venir les accusיs.
The rabbi...
Le rabbin,
the priest...
le prךtre
and the imam.
et l'imam.
It is like the old joke, yes?
C'est comme la vieille blague, non ?
The rabbi, the priest, and the imam.
Un rabbin, un prךtre et un imam.
Forgive me, I am Belgian.
Excusez-moi, je suis belge.
So, let us begin.
Commenחons.
In the Church of the Holy Sepulchre above us...
Lא-haut, dans l'יglise du Saint-Sיpulcre,
three representatives meet under the supervision...
trois reprיsentants se sont rיunis sous la supervision
of the Chief Inspector of Police
de l'inspecteur-chef de la police
to discuss a divided timetable for market use.
pour discuter de se rיpartir l'utilisation du marchי.
One hour after this tense meeting...
Une heure aprטs cette rיunion tendue,
a priceless relic is found to be stolen.
on a constatי le vol d'une relique inestimable.
It is said, one of these three men has stolen it.
On dit qu'un de ces trois hommes l'aurait prise.
The police find no pieces of evidence at all.
La police n'a trouvי aucun indice.
I find one.
Moi, oui.
On the meticulously well-kept wall of a fresco...
Sur le mur mיticuleusement prיservי d'une fresque,
a single crack from an indelicate climb...
une fissure causיe, en grimpant א la hגte,
with a hard-soled shoe or perhaps a boot.
par la semelle dure d'un soulier ou d'une botte.
So, ladies and gentlemen, we must ask...
Mesdames et messieurs, il convient de demander
who stands to benefit from the crime.
qui profite du crime.
Our three holy men live humbly.
Nos trois saints hommes vivent modestement.
They're thin-soled shoes poor.
Leurs semelles usיes tיmoignent de leur pauvretי.
Sudden riches and rubies would be...
Possיder soudain des rubis et des richesses serait
too conspicuous, yes, to enjoy. They do not gain.
trop ostentatoire. Ils n'en profiteraient pas.
At this point, we need an armed guard at the south gate.
Un garde armי doit protיger la porte sud.
Thank you very much.
Merci beaucoup.
No, the only one...
Non, le seul
who benefits from the theft and the unrest it causes...
qui profite du vol et du dיsordre en dיcoulant,
is a man whose office I had searched this morning...
c'est celui dont j'ai fait fouiller le bureau ce matin
as I waited, I have to tell you,
en attendant, je dois dire, un dיjeuner plutפt dיcevant.
Difficulty with eggs. You don't need to know this.
Un problטme d'ufs. Inutile de vous raconter חa.
A man who is paid lavishly to keep order in Jerusalem.
Un homme bien payי pour assurer la paix א Jיrusalem.
I mean, of course,
Je parle, bien sr,
the Chief Inspector of the Police.
de l'inspecteur-chef de la police.
A man who does not wish to lose a well-paid post...
Un homme qui s'accroche א un travail rיmunיrateur
when there is discussion
alors qu'il est question
among the local peoples of self-governance...
d'autogouvernance entre les peuples locaux.
who does wear boots, and who, I believe, now does regret...
Un homme chaussי de bottes, et qui regrette
inviting me to consult on this case.
d'avoir sollicitי mon avis sur l'affaire.
How dare you accuse me!
Comment osez-vous m'accuser ?
Please, Sergeant...
Sergent, je vous prie,
did you search the office as I asked?
avez-vous fouillי le bureau א ma demande ?
Uh, yes, sir.
Oui, monsieur.
And did you find what I said you might?
Et avez-vous trouvי ce que je soupחonnais ?
Uh, yes, sir. Just as you said.
Oui, monsieur. Comme vous l'aviez dit.
Halt!
Halte !
You need to deliver that, Captain.
Une livraison, capitaine. Elle doit partir demain matin.
Very good, sir.
Trטs bien, monsieur.
Luggage is on board, sir.
Vos bagages sont א bord, monsieur.
I won the right to escort you to your boat.
J'ai יtי chargי de vous escorter au bateau.
To Stamboul, then?
Cap sur Istanbul, alors ?
Will you be back to London straight off?
Retournerez-vous directement א Londres ?
I am tired, and I have earned myself a little holiday.
Je suis fatiguי et j'ai mיritי des vacances.
I want to look at paintings
Je veux admirer des tableaux
and have too much time on my hands.
et avoir du temps libre א ma disposition.
You are staring. Does it stop?
Vous me fixez. Pouvez-vous arrךter ?
It's just...
C'est juste que...
How did you know it was him, sir?
Comment avez-vous su que c'יtait lui
From just a tiny crack on the wall.
א partir d'une simple fissure sur le mur ?
I have the advantage...
J'ai un avantage.
I can only see the world as it should be.
Je vois le monde tel qu'il devrait ךtre.
And when it is not, the imperfection stands out...
Les imperfections me sautent aux yeux,
like the nose in the middle of a face.
aussi visibles qu'un nez au milieu du visage.
It makes most of life unbearable.
ַa me rend souvent la vie insupportable,
But it is useful in the detection of crime.
mais c'est utile pour dיtecter les crimes.
But it's as though you see into their hearts
C'est comme si vous voyiez au cur des gens
and divine their true natures.
et deviniez leur vraie nature.
And whatever people say,
Peu importe ce que certains affirment,
there is right, there is wrong.
il y a le bien et il y a le mal.
There is nothing in between.
Il n'y a rien entre les deux.
We must part here.
Nos routes se sיparent ici.
Oh, no, sir, I'm to escort you on the ferry.
Oh, non, monsieur. Je vous escorte א bord.
We must never meet again.
Nous ne nous reverrons jamais.
Could you straighten your tie, please? Just a little.
Pouvez-vous redresser un peu votre cravate ?
Yes. That is perfect.
- Oui. - C'est parfait.
Final passengers, please!
Derniers passagers, s'il vous plaמt !
Oh, I'm sorry.
Excusez-moi.
Will be fixed soon.
Ce sera vite rיparי.
But, will it be fixed in time?
Oui, mais terminerez-vous א temps ?
We are working!
On y travaille !
I have a connection in Stamboul.
J'ai une correspondance א Istanbul.
Leaves tomorrow at seven.
Dיpart demain א 19 h.
There's a very ill patient waiting for me in London.
Un patient trטs malade m'attend א Londres.
I am a doctor.
Je suis mיdecin.
Doctor.
Mיdecin.
I am shouting at you in English,
Je crie contre vous en anglais,
and now I'm doing it louder and slower.
bien lentement et bien fort.
Very silly, forgive me.
C'est ridicule. Pardon.
May I help? Let me help.
Puis-je vous aider ? Laissez-moi vous aider.
I know your mustache.
Je reconnais votre moustache.
From the papers.
Je vous ai vu dans le journal.
You're the detective, Hercules Poirot?
Vous ךtes le dיtective, Achille Poirot ?
Hercule Poirot. I do not slay the lions. Mademoiselle.
Hercule Poirot. Je n'ai pas de faiblesse. Mademoiselle.
Mary Debenham, monsieur.
Mary Debenham, monsieur.
I'll forget a name but never a face.
J'oublie les noms, mais jamais les visages.
Not yours, anyway.
Srement pas le vפtre, en tout cas.
You come from Baghdad?
Vous arrivez de Bagdad ?
It's true. No detail escapes his notice.
C'est donc vrai. Aucun dיtail ne lui יchappe.
Your ticket. Ah.
Votre billet.
I might also ask you if you enjoyed your time there...
Avez-vous apprיciי votre temps lא-bas
as a governess?
en tant que gouvernante ?
The chalk on your sleeve and the geography primer.
La craie sur votre manche et le manuel de gיographie.
A governess or a cartographer. I made my gamble.
Gouvernante ou cartographe. J'ai tentי ma chance.
I always begin them with geography...
Je leur enseigne d'abord la gיographie,
and monster them till they have the world down cold.
jusqu'א ce qu'ils connaissent le monde par cur.
They may get lost in life...
Mךme s'ils s'יgarent du droit chemin dans la vie,
but I'll be damned if they don't know where they are.
ils sauront toujours oש ils sont.
Well, our chains are free. Right on time.
Libיrיs de nos chaמnes, juste א temps.
I feel so free out here on the water.
Je me sens si libre ici, au large.
I wish I could enjoy it.
J'aimerais pouvoir en profiter.
We should be out of this, Mary.
Retirons-nous de l'affaire, Mary.
Not now.
Pas maintenant.
When it's all over.
Quand tout sera terminי.
When it's done.
Quand ce sera rיglי.
Then, nothing can touch us.
Alors, plus rien ne pourra nous toucher.
Ah, my holiday begins here.
Le dיbut de mes vacances.
I can see the soul of the city in these humble breads.
Je vois l'גme de la ville dans ces humbles pains.
The world insists on destruction, yet here...
Malgrי la destruction qui rטgne dans le monde,
masterpieces are baked to order every day.
on cuit des chefs-d'uvre sur demande chaque jour.
Monsieur Poirot!
M. Poirot !
Mohammed!
Mohammed !
Mohammed, my friend...
Mohammed, mon ami,
you are an artist.
vous ךtes un artiste.
Ah! My friend!
Mon ami !
Sorry.
Pardon.
Here. Come, come.
Par ici. Viens.
Don't mind us, we're just looking
Nous cherchons simplement
for a place to have a private argument.
un endroit oש nous disputer en privי.
It should take some 20 minutes or so...
Nous en aurons pour environ 20 minutes,
at which point we will both
aprטs quoi cela culminera
come to an agreement, or at least I will.
en une fin heureuse, du moins pour moi.
Monsieur Bouc!
M. Bouc !
Poirot! In the kitchen?
Poirot ! Dans la cuisine ?
Well, of course, this man will sniff out
ֹvidemment, cet homme flaire la piste
a perfect pastry faster than he catches...
d'une pגtisserie parfaite plus vite
a jewel thief.
que celle d'un voleur.
Now, I am no longer a policeman.
Je ne suis plus policier.
I cannot bail you out when this goes badly, eh?
Je ne vous sortirai pas du pיtrin avec elle.
This is my dear, old friend, the esteemed...
Voici mon vieil ami, le rיputי
Poirot, who I knew before the esteem.
Poirot, que j'ai connu avant tout le monde.
Hercule Poirot, this is...
Hercule Poirot, voici...
A prostitute. She is.
- Une prostituיe. - Oui.
I am. Bouc, you did not tell me you had famous friends.
Oui. Bouc, tu m'as cachי que tu as des amis cיlטbres.
We're friends because
On est amis parce que je suis le seul א ne pas poser
any questions about his cases, because I don't care.
de questions sur ses affaires. Je m'en fiche.
And he never judges me for being a terrible person.
Et il ne juge pas mes יcarts de conduite.
Indeed you are.
Tu es un vrai vaurien.
Madame, Bouc, please join me for a drink, yes?
Madame, Bouc, prendrez-vous un verre avec moi ?
You only have me for an hour.
Je ne resterai ici qu'une heure.
I ride on the Orient Express at seven,
Je prends l'Orient-Express א 19 h,
official director business.
affaires officielles du directeur.
Uncle pays me absurdly
Mon oncle me paie une fortune
to stay onboard his gorgeous train...
pour superviser son superbe train,
and far away from him...
loin de lui
at the home office...
et de son siטge social,
consigned to wine and dine
avec pour mission de charmer
handsome officials for all eternity.
des gens importants pour l'יternitי.
There is an art to nepotism.
Le nיpotisme est un art.
And you are its Michelangelo!
Et vous ךtes Michel-Ange !
Mr. Poirot.
M. Poirot.
Are you a prostitute as well?
Vous prostituez-vous aussi ?
Certainly not.
- Jamais de la vie. - Vous embךte-t-il ?
He is about to.
Il va le faire.
You are from the British consulate.
Vous ךtes du consulat britannique.
I am, sir. It is the Kassner case.
- En effet, monsieur. - L'affaire Kassner.
Why, yes.
Ma foi, c'est exact.
I was correct in certain predictions?
Mes prיdictions יtaient justes ?
Quite.
Plutפt.
I do not need to read the telegram.
Inutile que je lise le tיlיgramme.
Oh, how fun.
C'est fascinant.
Did someone cheat, or die?
Quelqu'un a יtי infidטle ou est mort ?
Unfortunately, both.
Les deux, malheureusement.
Someone has...
Quelqu'un a
interrupted my longing for rest.
perturbי le repos que je souhaitais tant.
It appears that I must travel with you tonight, Bouc.
Je dois partir avec vous ce soir, Bouc.
Can you find me a cabin on the Orient Express?
Trouvez-moi une cabine sur l'Orient-Express.
My friend...
Mon ami,
I may not be good for much, but I sure as hell
j'ai peu de talents, mais je peux srement
can get you a bed on my train...
vous trouver un lit dans mon train
in the dead of winter. Three days...
en plein hiver. Trois jours
free of care, concern or crime. You will love it.
sans soucis, scandales ou suspense. Vous adorerez.
Mademoiselle, it has been a pleasure. Sir.
Un plaisir, mademoiselle. Monsieur.
Your luggage has been collected
On a ramassי vos bagages et payי vos dיpenses.
You will be met at Calais...
On viendra vous chercher א Calais
and then escorted to Dover,
pour vous escorter jusqu'א Douvres,
and then by rail to London Victoria.
puis א la gare Victoria de Londres.
I would like to formally
J'aimerais officiellement
express gratitude. Please, don't speak.
- exprimer ma gratitude. - Chut !
You make it worse.
Vous empirez les choses.
Here's a tip for you, pal. Thank you, Mr. Marquez.
- Un pourboire pour vous. - Merci, M. Marquez.
I didn't even carry your luggage.
Je n'ai mךme pas portי vos sacs.
Oh, I had a good week.
Oh, j'ai eu une bonne semaine.
We celebrate when fortune smiles,
Quand la fortune nous sourit, on fךte
and we share the good fortune.
et on la partage.
Remember to say nice things about us Americans, huh?
Vous direz de bonnes choses de nous, les Amיricains.
No!
Non !
Hey, stop!
Hי ! Arrךtez !
For you, Mr. Ratchett,
Pour vous, M. Ratchett,
the best table in the house.
la meilleure table de la maison.
Just here, sir. The very best table.
Juste ici, monsieur. La meilleure de toutes.
No, I want that one.
Non, je veux celle-lא.
Hey, Masterman. You got everything?
Bonsoir, Masterman. Vous avez tout ?
Kind of you to inquire, Mr. MacQueen.
C'est gentil de le demander, M. MacQueen.
I do not make mistakes.
Je ne commets pas d'erreurs.
Oh, my goodness! It's Count Andrenyi.
Bontי divine ! C'est le comte Andrenyi.
Come, come, come.
Venez, venez.
I saw you dance at the Monte Cristo.
Je vous ai vu danser au Monte Cristo.
Could I take your photograph?
Puis-je vous prendre en photo ?
Please, my face, no!
Mon visage, non !
Sorry.
Excusez-moi.
The Simplon Orient Express...
L'Orient-Express de Simplon,
with stops in Sofia, Niš, Belgrade, Vinkovci, Brod...
avec arrךts א Sofia, Ni, Belgrade, Vinkovci et Brod,
with transfers to Bucharest, Zagreb,
correspondances pour Bucarest, Zagreb,
Trieste, Venezia, Milan, Lausanne...
Trieste, Venise, Milan, Lausanne,
Dijon, Paris, Boulogne, Calais...
Dijon, Paris, Boulogne, Calais
with connection to Dover and London,
et liaison pour Douvres et Londres
leaves in fifteen minutes!
part dans 15 minutes !
This way, Michel! Precious cargo.
Par ici, Michel ! Marchandise prיcieuse.
I need a first-class compartment.
Il me faut une cabine de premiטre classe.
Give special care to my friend, Michel.
Prenez bien soin de mon ami, Michel.
I want him pampered like a zoo panda.
Dorlotez-le comme un panda au zoo.
But Monsieur Bouc, we are fully booked.
Mais M. Bouc, c'est complet. Il ne reste aucune place.
Then we make space. He can have the number eleven.
On lui en fera une. Donnez-lui la 11.
The eleven is always kept open for official use.
On la garde libre pour usage officiel.
It's very comfortable.
Elle est trטs confortable.
Eleven is taken.
La 11 est occupיe.
The Austrian professor booked it two days ago.
Le professeur autrichien l'a prise.
There is not one first-class
Il ne reste aucune cabine en premiטre de tout le train ?
Negative, sir.
Non, monsieur.
Second-class? There's no space left at all.
- En deuxiטme ? - Pas la moindre place.
Mademoiselle Debenham.
Mlle Debenham.
Mr. Poirot, are you joining us?
M. Poirot, vous joignez-vous א nous ?
It depends who wins this debate.
Tout dיpend de qui gagne ce dיbat.
Have all the passengers arrived?
Tous les passagers sont arrivיs ?
All but one. Mr. Harris.
Tous sauf M. Harris.
"All passengers must check in
"Les passagers doivent s'enregistrer
"at least one half hour prior to time of departure...
"une demi-heure avant l'heure du dיpart
"or their seat may be forfeit."
"ou risquent de perdre leur place."
The half hour has passed. The seat is forfeit.
La demi-heure est יcoulיe. Il a perdu sa place.
Please take Monsieur Poirot's luggage
Portez les bagages de M. Poirot
to number three with Mr. MacQueen.
א la cabine numיro trois, avec M. MacQueen.
Merci, Bouc. Enjoy, my friend.
- Merci, Bouc. - Profitez-en, mon ami.
Welcome, sir. Merci.
Bienvenue, monsieur.
Number three is unlucky.
Le chiffre trois porte malchance.
Apologies, madame. I meant no disrespect.
Pardon, je ne voulais pas vous manquer de respect.
Well, you could try to mean a little.
Vous pourriez bien essayer.
One thing about train travel,
Quand on voyage en train,
you're always knocking into somebody.
on se frotte toujours aux autres.
It's wonderful.
C'est merveilleux.
Though, I am looking forward to getting back.
J'ai hגte de rentrer chez moi.
Travel is fine for spicy food, mosques, meeting men.
Les יpices, les mosquיes, rencontrer des hommes,
But eventually, you just miss your own bed.
c'est bien, mais mon lit finit par me manquer.
I've been accused of husband hunting abroad.
On m'accuse de chercher un mari א l'יtranger.
Well, I can't, in all honesty, deny it.
Honnךtement, je ne peux pas le nier.
I like my time alone, I do.
J'aime bien ךtre seule, c'est vrai.
But a lady has certain needs
Mais une dame a certains besoins
that deserve to be met if she has any money...
qui mיritent d'ךtre comblיs si elle a de l'argent,
and preferably, on a regular basis.
de prיfיrence avec rיgularitי.
Farewell, madame.
Au revoir, madame.
Good evening.
Bonsoir.
Number nine.
Numיro neuf.
How you doing? Bonsoir.
Comment allez-vous ? Bonsoir.
No, after you.
Non, aprטs vous.
Yeah. I think you might have the wrong berth.
Oui. Je crois que vous vous trompez de cabine.
The train is full.
Le train est plein.
I think that we are, how do you say... "bunkies."
Nous serons... quel est le mot ? Cochambreurs.
Really?
Ah bon ?
I am equally disappointed in you. This is nice.
Vous me dיcevez יgalement. C'est bien, ici.
Come along, darlings.
Venez, mes chיris.
No.
Non.
This?
Ici ?
Why am I not yet unpacked?
Pourquoi mes valises ne sont-elles pas dיfaites ?
Five minutes to departure.
Dיpart dans cinq minutes.
Final call for passengers!
Dernier appel pour tous les passagers !
Shall we brush you?
Veux-tu qu'on te brosse ?
What the hell is taking them so long?
Qu'est-ce qui leur prend si longtemps ?
Soon as we get out of here, have them make up the bed.
Demandez qu'on fasse le lit dטs le dיpart.
It's already arranged, Mr. Ratchett.
C'est dיjא prיvu, M. Ratchett.
No, I want the bed made. And bring my Dictaphone.
Non. Je veux mon lit. Et apportez mon dictaphone.
Dogs on the table.
Des chiens sur la table.
Most disgusting thing I've ever seen in my life.
C'est ce que j'ai vu de plus dיgotant de ma vie.
Yes, sir. I want you to get MacQueen...
- Oui, monsieur. - Allez chercher MacQueen
and have him bring every receipt from the Milan sale.
et demandez-lui d'apporter les reחus de Milan.
I want you to get it done. Yes, sir.
- Faites-le. - Oui, monsieur.
I want you to get it done now.
Faites-le tout de suite.
Did I say get it done now? Right away, sir.
- Ai-je dit tout de suite. - Oui, monsieur.
"Better watch yourself."
"Surveillez vos arriטres."
Your coffee, Mr. Ratchett.
Votre cafי, M. Ratchett.
Who did this?
Qui a fait חa ?
I can't say, sir.
Je ne saurais pas dire, monsieur.
Good evening, Mrs. Hubbard.
Bonsoir, Mme Hubbard.
Hello there, Mr. Masterman.
Bonsoir, M. Masterman.
Well, hello.
Bonsoir.
Eyes linger any longer, I'll have to charge rent.
Si ce regard s'יternise, je lui demanderai un loyer.
I'll pay.
Je paierai.
Are you insulted?
tes-vous insultיe ?
Some men have a good look.
Les hommes se rincent l'il.
All they have to do is...
Tout ce qu'ils ont א faire,
keep their mouth shut,
c'est garder le silence
and they can take home any prize they want.
pour ramener le prix de leur choix א la maison.
Still, the mouth opens.
Et pourtant, ils ouvrent la bouche.
Is everything all right, Mrs. Hubbard?
Tout va bien, Mme Hubbard ?
You have a strong intuition, I know.
Vous ךtes trטs intuitive, je le sais.
My second husband used to say just so.
C'est ce que disait mon deuxiטme mari.
Hold that, it was my first.
Non, attendez, c'יtait mon premier.
Yeah.
Oui.
Brightest man I ever met.
L'homme le plus brillant que j'aie connu.
Face like a turnip, but I loved that turnip.
Un visage de navet, mais j'adorais ce navet.
It was nice to talk.
Content de vous avoir parlי.
Good night.
Bonne nuit.
Voilà.
Voilא.
I will move Monsieur MacQueen
je dיmיnagerai M. MacQueen dans la cabine de M. Bouc.
You travel first class, monsieur.
Vous voyagez en 1re classe, monsieur.
Good afternoon.
Bon aprטs-midi.
Ah, Mrs. Hubbard.
Mme Hubbard.
There we are.
Tenez.
Compliments of the Orient Express.
Gracieusetי de l'Orient-Express.
Thank you, Mr. Bouc.
Merci, M. Bouc.
I am here for all of your needs.
Je suis lא pour tous vos besoins.
No, thank you. I do not drink.
Non, merci. Je ne bois pas d'alcool.
It does not agree with you?
Vous le digיrez mal ?
Sin does not agree with me.
C'est le pיchי que je digטre mal.
Vice is where the devil finds his darlings.
C'est dans le vice que le diable trouve ses amis.
We should no longer speak.
Je ne devrais plus vous parler.
Good afternoon.
Bon aprטs-midi.
Monsieur. How about a apéritif?
Monsieur. Prenez donc l'apיritif avec nous.
I regret I have an appointment
Je regrette, mais j'ai rendez-vous
with the director of the train.
avec le directeur du train.
He was gonna leave anyway.
Il allait partir de toute faחon.
Please, sir. Madame, madame.
Je vous en prie, monsieur.
All settled in?
Bien installי ?
And yet, the best things on the train are not food.
Ce qu'il y a de mieux א bord ne se mange pas.
You know there's something about...
Il y a quelque chose א propos
a tangle of strangers pressed together
d'יtrangers coincיs ensemble
for days on end, with nothing in common...
pendant des jours, sans rien en commun
but the need to go from one place to another...
sauf le besoin d'aller d'un endroit א un autre,
then never to see each other again.
et qui ne se reverront jamais.
Boredom plus anonymity plus a...
Un mיlange d'ennui, d'anonymat et de...
constant, gentle rocking.
doux bercement constant.
With your hobbies, you will never amount to anything.
Avec vos passe-temps, vous n'accomplirez rien.
God, I hope so. Hmm.
Seigneur, j'espטre bien.
Order me the fish.
Commandez-moi le poisson.
Um, exchange grouper for sole,
De la sole au lieu du mיrou,
escarole for the potato, and...
avec pomme de terre au lieu de l'escarole
the beef sauce for the velouté.
et veloutי au lieu de la sauce au buf.
Garçon, that sounds superb. The same for me.
ַa me semble dיlicieux. Mךme chose pour moi.
The Princess Dragomiroff.
La princesse Dragomiroff.
You know, if I ever were to marry for money,
S'il fallait que je me marie pour l'argent,
I'd marry for that much money.
je dirais oui א une telle fortune.
I brushed Dalia this morning.
J'ai brossי Dalia ce matin.
No, you tortured my darling doggy.
Non. Vous avez torturי ma chienne adorיe.
I asked you to brush her.
Je vous ai demandי de la brosser.
Are you still enjoying your Dickens?
Le Dickens vous plaמt-il toujours ?
Very much, mon ami.
Beaucoup, mon ami.
You know, with your books and your capers,
Avec vos livres et vos enquךtes,
you are missing out on romance.
votre vie manque de romantisme.
Romance never goes unpunished.
Le romantisme ne s'en tire jamais impuni.
There was, uh...
Il y a eu...
There was someone once.
Il y a eu quelqu'un autrefois.
I would prefer, in the future, to be sat not with that man.
Je prיfיrerais ne plus ךtre assis avec lui.
Like should be seated with like.
On devrait ךtre assis entre semblables.
We are not alike.
Il n'est pas mon semblable.
Not all of us are so concerned
Tout le monde n'est pas si prיoccupי
with the separateness of races, Professor.
par la sיgrיgation des races, professeur.
It is out of respect for all kinds
C'est par respect pour chaque race
that I prefer to keep them separate.
que je prיfטre les garder sיparיes.
To mix your red wine and the white
Mיlanger du vin rouge et du vin blanc
would be to ruin them both.
ne ferait que les gגcher tous les deux.
I like a good rosé.
J'aime le bon rosי.
Hey, how you doing? Would you mind...
Comment allez-vous ? Me permettez-vous
if I joined you?
de me joindre א vous ?
Dessert is an indulgence...
Le dessert est une gגterie,
and I feel kinda silly and stupid indulging alone.
et je me sens ridicule quand je me gגte seul.
I am at my happiest alone.
C'est seul que je suis le plus heureux.
But...
Mais...
for a small piece of your fragelité,
en יchange d'une bouchיe de ce dיlice,
please join me.
vous pouvez vous joindre א moi.
Oh, with pleasure. Excuse me, another fork?
Avec plaisir. Une autre fourchette ?
I've been trying to make your acquaintance, Mr. Poirot.
Je souhaitais faire votre connaissance, M. Poirot.
I never ever sat so close to fame before.
Je n'ai jamais יtי si proche d'une cיlיbritי.
No, I tell a lie.
Non, c'est faux.
Once, I was on a bus with Ty Cobb.
J'ai dיjא pris l'autobus avec Ty Cobb.
Ball player, Detroit. Ah.
Baseballeur, de Detroit.
Would you mind if I have the little curly bit at the top?
Je peux prendre la petite dיcoration ?
You're an odd bird there.
Vous ךtes יtrange.
You're a strange, peculiar man.
Vous ךtes un homme hors du commun.
I am of an age
ְ l'גge que j'ai,
where I know what I like and what I do not like.
je sais ce que j'aime et ce que je n'aime pas.
What I like, I enjoy enormously.
J'adore ce que j'aime.
What I dislike, I cannot abide.
Je ne supporte pas ce que je n'aime pas.
For instance, the temporary pleasantries
Par exemple, l'amabilitי temporaire
before what is determined to be a business discussion.
avant une discussion d'affaires.
You're fun.
On s'amuse bien avec vous.
All right.
Trטs bien.
I would like to offer you a job.
J'ai du travail א vous proposer.
"The avenger of the innocent."
"Dיfenseur des innocents." C'est votre surnom.
And you are an innocent?
Et vous ךtes un innocent ?
I'm a businessman.
Je suis un homme d'affaires.
I'm an art dealer. I mean, I'm new to it.
Un marchand d'art, nouveau dans le mיtier.
But my beginner's luck has panned out.
La chance du dיbutant m'a souri.
Relics, antiquities.
Des reliques, des antiquitיs.
Rugs, weird. Orientals.
D'יtranges tapis orientaux.
I'm new to the game, so I got the amateur eyeball.
J'ai l'il d'un amateur, vu mon peu d'expיrience.
But I got a little problem with these, uh...
Mais j'ai un petit problטme avec les...
so-called appraisers.
prיtendus יvaluateurs.
You can't trust a one of 'em.
Aucun n'est digne de confiance.
Some of my customers...
Certains de mes clients
they buy a piece...
achטtent une uvre,
they find out that they're not exactly original...
puis constatent qu'elle n'est pas originale.
which is hardly my fault...
Ce n'est pas ma faute
if a Kashan silk scarf is a fake.
si une soie de Kashan est contrefaite.
Right? Huh?
N'est-ce pas ?
But I've managed to make a few enemies, is the thing.
J'ai malheureusement rיussi א me faire quelques ennemis.
I got a few letters, people making threats.
J'ai reחu des lettres de menaces.
I think, most likely, it's the Italians.
Je crois qu'elles viennent des Italiens.
I sold them a set of Oriental carpets in Milan.
J'ai vendu des tapis orientaux א Milan.
And the buyers weren't so happy with the provenance.
Les acheteurs sont insatisfaits de la provenance.
And they want their money back with interest, you know?
Ils veulent ךtre remboursיs avec intיrךts.
Italians.
Les Italiens.
A guinea's a guinea.
Un Rital, c'est un Rital.
And then comes along the genius detective.
C'est lא qu'entre en scטne le dיtective de gיnie.
Me?
Moi ?
Yes, you. Hercules Poirot. Hercule.
- Oui, vous, Achille Poirot. - Hercule.
Here's what I'd like to do.
Voici ce que j'aimerais faire.
I would like to hire you to watch my back...
J'aimerais vous engager comme garde du corps
until I get someplace safe.
jusqu'א ce que je sois en sretי.
It's easy money for you.
C'est de l'argent facile pour vous
And it's peace of mind for me, you know?
et חa assure ma tranquillitי d'esprit.
I understand. Good.
- Je comprends. - Bien.
I refuse.
Je refuse.
I'm sorry? That's bad.
Pardon ? Il ne faut pas.
Maybe I didn't make myself clear enough.
Je n'ai peut-ךtre pas יtי clair.
You see, someone's out to get me.
Quelqu'un veut ma peau.
And I know I'm not the best guy born, not by a long shot.
Je ne suis pas un ange, loin de lא.
And if there's a world after this one,
Si un autre monde nous attend,
I will face judgment just like you.
je recevrai mon jugement, tout comme vous.
But...
Mais...
I ain't in no goddamn rush to do it.
Je ne suis pas pressי d'en arriver lא.
You're holding a gun on me? No.
- Me prenez-vous pour cible ? - Non.
Not you. On the world.
Pas vous. Le monde.
I exist in the world. Do not point a gun at me.
J'existe dans le monde. Ne me prenez pas pour cible.
How's ten thousand sound for a week?
Que dites-vous de 10 000 $ par semaine ?
It's a generous offer, Mr. Ratchett. I must decline.
C'est gיnיreux, M. Ratchett, mais je refuse.
Fifteen thousand?
Quinze mille ?
You didn't hear me. I decline.
Comprenez-moi bien. Je refuse.
Oh, I get it.
Je vois.
It's not flashy enough for the great Hercules Poirot, huh?
Pas assez prestigieux pour le grand Achille Poirot ?
No flashbulbs...
Pas d'appareils photo...
You sell fakes to gangsters.
Vente de faux א des criminels.
You're suffering the consequences.
Vous en souffrez les consיquences.
I detect criminals. I do not protect them.
Je dיbusque les criminels. Je ne les protטge pas.
So you say "no" to my dirty money.
Vous dites donc non א mon argent sale.
I say "no" to you, Mr. Ratchett.
C'est א vous que je dis non, M. Ratchett.
Business with the gun, right? Is that what it was?
C'est l'arme, le problטme, c'est חa ?
It is far more personal than that.
C'est bien plus personnel que חa.
I do not like your face.
Votre tךte ne me revient pas.
If you will excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
You liked my cake, didn't you?
Vous avez aimי mon gגteau, pas vrai ?
The cake was excellent.
Il יtait excellent. Bon aprטs-midi, M. Ratchett.
Thank you.
Merci.
Mr. Ratchett?
M. Ratchett ?
Good night.
Bonne nuit.
Mrs. Hubbard?
Mme Hubbard ?
It's always Mrs. Hubbard.
C'est toujours Mme Hubbard.
Mrs. Hubbard.
Mme Hubbard.
Did we die?
Est-ce qu'on est morts ?
Ladies and gentlemen, the train has been derailed.
Un dיraillement, mesdames et messieurs.
Are you all right, Mr. Marquez?
ַa va, M. Marquez ?
I'm fine. Thank you.
Je n'ai rien, merci.
Mr. Bouc will speak to you all...
M. Bouc s'adressera א vous tous
in the morning.
demain matin.
Please, you will be safest in your cabins.
Vos cabines sont un endroit sr.
Of course.
Certainement.
Are we gonna die?
Allons-nous mourir ?
Ladies and gentlemen, I am afraid
Mesdames et messieurs, je crains
that our train is still unable to go anywhere.
que notre train ne puisse aller nulle part.
Yeah, except down.
Sauf vers le bas.
How long are we supposed to just sit here?
Combien de temps faut-il attendre ici ?
Yes, someone must be doing something.
Quelqu'un va srement intervenir.
Of course I am doing something. I am doing nothing.
Bien sr que oui. Nul besoin d'agir.
Precisely two hours and ten minutes ago,
Il y a exactement deux heures et dix minutes,
when we did not arrive in Brod as scheduled...
heure א laquelle nous devions arriver א Brod,
the station master will have surmised our situation...
le chef de gare aura devinי notre situation
and already dispatched a team to excavate the engine...
et envoyי une יquipe dיgager la locomotive,
clear our path, and send us on our way.
dיblayer les rails et nous aider א repartir.
Until then, I assure you...
En attendant, je vous assure
we will all be made warm and fed and comfortable.
qu'on sera tous au chaud, nourris et bien א l'aise.
We could walk.
On pourrait sortir marcher.
We could die of exposure trying.
Et mourir de froid par le fait mךme.
I have a connection to make.
J'ai une correspondance.
My boat sails day after tomorrow from France.
Mon bateau quittera la France aprטs-demain.
Without you, I'd wager. Or me in London.
Sans vous א bord. Ni moi א Londres.
I hold you accountable for my loss of time, Mr. Bouc.
Je vous tiens responsable du retard, M. Bouc.
Madam, you cannot hold me accountable for the weather.
Je ne suis pas responsable de la mיtיo.
Of course I can. You're the one here.
Bien sr que oui. Qui d'autre ?
And my conference in Turin?
Et ma confיrence א Turin ?
And I was to meet at the auto factory in Sochaux.
J'ai une rיunion א l'usine de voitures de Sochaux.
Yes, some things, they are in God's hands.
Certaines choses sont entre les mains de Dieu.
It is not for us to say...
Ce n'est pas א nous de dire
if we deserve to arrive safely at our destination...
si nous mיritons d'arriver en sretי א destination
or if, like Lucifer, we must fall.
ou si, comme Lucifer, la chute nous attend.
Breakfast for you, Mr. Ratchett.
Votre dיjeuner, M. Ratchett.
Ah, Bonjour, Mr. Masterman.
Ah, bonjour, M. Masterman.
There is a problem?
Y a-t-il un problטme ?
I can't say, sir.
Je n'en sais rien, monsieur.
Mr. Ratchett?
M. Ratchett ?
Excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
That is cold air.
L'air est froid.
Please bring Monsieur Bouc immediately,
Appelez vite M. Bouc et le Dr Arbuthnot.
Good God!
Seigneur !
Touch nothing else, only the body.
Ne touchez א rien sauf au corps.
My God, this is horrible.
Mon Dieu, c'est terrible.
First the snow, now...
D'abord la neige, et א prיsent...
I'll have to meet with the police
Je devrai parler א la police
and make some statement in some grimy station.
et faire ma dיposition dans un poste miteux.
And a man has died.
En plus, un homme est mort.
He was stabbed.
Il a יtי poignardי.
Long, straight-edged knife.
Un long couteau א lame droite.
Multiple stab wounds, some shallow,
De multiples blessures, tant superficielles
some cut clean through muscle.
que profondes, tranchant les muscles.
Left-hand side or right-hand side?
Gaucher ou droitier ?
That's the thing.
Justement.
It appears the killer
On dirait que le tueur
maybe closed his eyes and struck blind.
a fermי les yeux et frappי א l'aveuglette.
Can you estimate the time of death?
Heure estimיe du dיcטs ?
It's hard to say with the window open...
Dur א dire avec la fenךtre ouverte,
but my best guess is between midnight and 2:00.
mais je dirais entre minuit et 2 h.
But no one went in his compartment then.
Personne n'est entrי lא.
I sat in my seat all night.
J'יtais au poste toute la nuit.
I would have seen if someone went in. It's impossible.
Si quelqu'un יtait entrי, je l'aurais vu. Impossible.
Thank you, Doctor. Please, return to the dining car.
Merci. Retournez א la voiture-restaurant.
Michel, secure this carriage.
Michel, sיcurisez ce wagon.
Poirot.
Poirot.
I need your help, my friend.
J'ai besoin de votre aide, mon ami.
You have to find who did this.
Vous devez dיmasquer le coupable.
Please, I implore you,
Je vous en implore, au nom de l'Orient-Express.
When the police arrive,
Quand la police arrivera, je veux que ce soit rיglי.
You are the only one who can save me.
Vous seul pouvez me sauver.
Your faith touches me, mon cher.
Votre confiance me touche, mon cher,
But I must have this rest.
mais j'ai besoin de repos.
Well, think of it as a little beachside puzzle.
Voyez cela comme une petite יnigme de vacances.
That's nothing to your mind!
Ce n'est rien pour un cerveau comme le vפtre !
You look up the antecedents of the passengers.
Fouillez les antיcיdents des passagers.
You establish their bona fides.
Dיterminez leur caractטre.
Then you do what you do. You... You... You...
Faites ce que vous faites. Vous... Vous...
You sit in a chair and you eat your cake...
Vous vous asseyez en mangeant du gגteau
and you think until the solution presents itself.
et vous rיflיchissez jusqu'א trouver une solution.
What else are you going to do while we sit here in the snow?
On est coincיs. Qu'avez-vous d'autre א faire ?
Without constant stimulation,
Sans stimulation constante, vos neurones affamיs mourront.
You think that is what I do? I sit in a chair...
Vous croyez que je m'assieds
and I have a little piece of cake,
pour manger du gגteau
and then I come up with a great idea?
et qu'une grande idיe me vient ?
I don't know what you do. I have my Dickens.
- Je l'ignore. - J'ai mon Dickens.
Damn your Dickens!
Au diable votre Dickens !
If we leave this to the police,
Si la police s'en mךle, elle choisira un coupable,
right or wrong, and they will hang him.
א tort ou א raison, et le fera pendre.
Most probably Mr. Marquez...
Probablement M. Marquez,
for no other reason than his name is Marquez.
simplement parce qu'il s'appelle Marquez.
Or Dr. Arbuthnot for the color of his skin.
Ou le Dr Arbuthnot, pour la couleur de sa peau.
You are the only one who can bring justice.
Vous seul pouvez rendre justice.
Let me have a map of this coach.
- Donnez-moi un plan du wagon. - Bien sr.
Every passport. Anything.
- Chaque passeport. - Entendu.
Interviews arranged with all of our passengers.
Prיvoyez des entrevues avec chaque passager.
Evidence, order and method, until one culprit emerges.
Preuves, ordre et mיthode nous conduiront au coupable.
I do not approve of murder, my friend.
Je dיsapprouve le meurtre, mon ami.
Every day, we meet people
On croise chaque jour des gens
the world could do better without...
dont on se passerait,
yet we do not kill them.
mais on ne les tue pas.
We must be better than the beasts.
L'homme est supיrieur א la bךte.
So let us find this killer.
Trouvons donc ce tueur.
What's going on?
Que se passe-t-il ?
Ladies and gentlemen, allow me to, um...
Mesdames et messieurs, permettez-moi de...
It appears that our bad luck has worsened.
La malchance s'acharne sur nous.
That is...
Je veux dire que...
A passenger has died on the train.
Un passager est mort dans le train.
Monsieur Ratchett.
M. Ratchett.
Looks like they got him after all.
Ils ont eu sa peau aprטs tout.
You assume he was killed?
Vous prיsumez qu'il a יtי tuי ?
No, no.
Non, non.
I just mean he was in perfectly good health.
Seulement, il יtait en excellente santי.
He had his enemies, that's all.
Il avait des ennemis, c'est tout.
Indeed, he did. He was murdered.
En effet. Il a יtי assassinי.
Good God. Murder, here?
Bontי divine. Un meurtre, ici ?
Alas, madame.
Hיlas, madame.
God rest his soul.
Que Dieu ait son גme.
Someone was rummaging around my cabin
Quelqu'un est entrי dans ma cabine
in the middle of the night.
en pleine nuit.
Nobody would believe me.
Personne ne m'a crue.
What is going on?
Que se passe-t-il ?
As we are snowbound,
ֹtant coincי par la neige,
I have elected to take the case...
j'accepte de m'attaquer א l'affaire
and find for my friend, Monsieur Bouc, the criminal.
et de trouver le criminel pour mon ami, M. Bouc.
And why you?
Pourquoi vous ?
My name is Hercule Poirot...
Je m'appelle Hercule Poirot.
and I am probably the greatest detective in the world.
Je suis probablement l'as des dיtectives.
I will speak to all of you in time.
Je parlerai א chacun d'entre vous.
For the moment...
Pour l'instant,
I must recommend that you remain
je vous conseille de rester
in your compartments with the doors locked.
dans votre cabine, porte verrouillיe.
I feel like a prisoner here.
Je me sens comme une prisonniטre.
It is for your own safety.
C'est pour votre sיcuritי.
If there was a murder...
S'il y a eu un meurtre,
then there was a murderer.
c'est qu'il y a un meurtrier.
The murderer is with us...
Ce meurtrier est avec nous
on the train, now.
א bord du train en ce moment.
The doors between coaches were locked at night, hmm?
Les portes entre les wagons יtaient bien verrouillיes ?
Absolutely. Done myself.
Tout א fait. J'y ai vu moi-mךme.
The train's been searched.
Le train a יtי fouillי. Personne ne s'y cache.
We can therefore limit our investigation
On peut limiter l'enquךte aux occupants du wagon Calais.
Bouc, you will assist me.
Bouc, vous m'aiderez.
As the only traveler who slept in another coach...
Vous ךtes le seul א avoir dormi ailleurs,
you are the only one who is not a suspect.
et donc le seul qui n'est pas un suspect.
Mr. MacQueen, is this really the time for drinking?
M. MacQueen, est-ce le moment de boire ?
My boss is dead.
Mon patron est mort.
I'm out of a job,
Je n'ai plus d'emploi,
and you're looking at me like I did it.
et vous me jetez des regards accusateurs.
We make no accusations.
Nous n'accusons personne.
You knew him, so from here
Puisque vous le connaissiez, vous nous donnerez les faits.
Were you his relative?
ֹtiez-vous parents ?
No, his secretary.
Non, j'יtais son secrיtaire.
Book his travel, order his steaks.
Je rיservais ses voyages, commandais ses biftecks.
The man ate more steak
Je n'avais encore connu personne
than I've ever seen in my entire life.
qui mange autant de biftecks.
He was in antiques.
Il travaillait dans les antiquitיs
He had no qualification for it,
Il n'יtait pas qualifiי pour חa,
not the eye or the languages.
n'avait pas les compיtences.
Truth is, he had no head for business, accounting...
Il n'avait pas le sens des affaires, des comptes,
none of it.
rien de tout חa.
I took care of everything.
Je m'occupais de tout.
How long were you in his employ?
Depuis quand יtiez-vous son employי ?
Twenty days shy of a year.
ַa aurait fait un an dans 20 jours.
Prohibition wasn't to my taste...
La prohibition, ce n'יtait pas pour moi.
so I found myself overseas, and in debt.
Je me suis retrouvי א l'יtranger, endettי.
I'm a lawyer by education...
Je suis avocat de formation,
not disposition.
mais pas de tempיrament.
I was downright awful at it.
J'יtais trטs mauvais.
You were fond of him?
Aimiez-vous votre patron ?
I was fond of his money.
J'aimais son argent.
Ratchett was crude...
Ratchett יtait grossier,
demanding, insulting, and most likely a felon.
exigeant, insultant et probablement un criminel.
When did you last see him?
Quand l'avez-vous vu pour la derniטre fois ?
It must have been just after 10:00.
Juste aprטs 22 h.
He called me in to go over our sales in Italy.
Il voulait discuter de nos ventes en Italie.
Milan, the sale of forgeries?
Milan, la vente de faux ?
Yeah, yeah.
Oui.
He wanted to look over the accounts.
Il voulait examiner les comptes.
I had to translate everything...
Je devais tout traduire pour lui,
as the contracts were in French
les contrats יtant en franחais.
and he didn't speak a word.
Il n'en parlait pas un mot.
And when we stopped at Vinkovci...
Et lors de l'arrךt א Vinkovci,
I struck up a chat with the colored doctor, Arbuthnot.
j'ai bavardי avec le mיdecin noir, Arbuthnot.
And we had a couple of drinks, stretched our legs.
On a bu quelques verres, on s'est dיgourdi les jambes.
He had some...
Il avait quelques
odd opinions about Stalin I had to turn around.
opinions que je devais rectifier א propos de Staline.
I don't hold a man's race against him,
Je ne juge pas un homme א sa race,
but I don't often take to Britishers.
mais je m'entends mal avec les Britanniques.
When did your party end?
ְ quelle heure vous ךtes-vous sיparיs ?
He left just after 2:00.
Il est parti juste aprטs 2 h.
Did you know of any specific enemies
Savez-vous si Ratchett avait des ennemis particuliers ?
Gosh.
Seigneur.
Pick a number.
Choisissez votre homme.
He confided he had been threatened?
Avait-il reחu des menaces ?
He got a couple of nasty letters.
Certaines lettres inquiיtantes, oui.
I have them if you like. Some, anyway.
Je peux vous en remettre quelques-unes.
He tore up the rest.
Il a dיchirי les autres.
Threw them into the fire.
Il les a jetיes au feu.
That's them.
Les voici.
Merci, Mr. MacQueen.
Merci, M. MacQueen.
Uh, thank you.
Merci.
If we have any further questions,
Si on a d'autres questions, on redemandera א vous parler.
Have you considered the Latin man?
Avez-vous pensי א l'Hispanique ?
Marquez. Hell of a guy.
Marquez. Tout un homme.
And, well, you know, his kind...
Vous savez ce qu'on dit de son peuple.
they don't have the same distaste for murder,
Ils ne partagent pas notre dיdain pour le meurtre,
historically speaking.
historiquement parlant.
You said you don't hold a man's race against him.
Vous disiez ne pas juger un homme א sa race.
I suppose...
Je suppose
depends on the race.
que חa dיpend de la race.
And he was doing so well.
Il s'en tirait si bien.
You think it's MacQueen? Too early to say.
- C'est MacQueen ? - Trop tפt pour le dire.
I admit, I cannot see him
J'avoue que je l'imagine mal poignarder un homme 12 fois.
Not sober, anyway. Who did it then?
Enfin, pas sobre. Qui l'a fait, alors ?
I do not know yet. It is time we ask.
Je l'ignore. Il faut le demander.
Ask who? The victim.
- ְ qui ? - ְ la victime.
He has twelve stab wounds
Douze coups de couteau,
and, as Arbuthnot said, they are patternless.
portיs au hasard selon Arbuthnot.
If the doctor is guilty...
Si le mיdecin est coupable,
he certainly did not let it influence
il n'a pas laissי ce fait influencer
his responsibilities.
ses responsabilitיs.
Hey, the watch. Stopped at 1:15.
Sa montre s'est arrךtיe א 1 h 15.
Now that agrees with the doctor on the time of death.
ַa concorde avec les dires du mיdecin.
Hmm. It is possible, yes. Certainly possible.
Possible, oui. Certainement.
I don't quite understand.
- Je ne comprends pas. - Moi non plus.
I understand nothing at all.
Je ne comprends rien du tout.
If you look at these two wounds...
Regardez ces deux blessures.
they are powerful and deep, and yet there is little blood.
Puissantes, profondes, mais il y a peu de sang.
But this was a frenzied attack.
C'יtait pourtant une attaque frיnיtique.
Lashing here and there.
Des lacיrations ici et lא.
No pattern at all, just extreme violence.
Aucun ordre, que de la violence extrךme.
And during all this, our victim,
Pendant ce temps, notre victime,
vigorous and anxious and full of coffee...
vigoureuse, nerveuse et bourrיe de cafי,
merely lies still and accepts death without struggle...
serait restיe immobile, sans lutter contre la mort,
when he also has here...
alors qu'elle avait sous la main
the means by which he might defend himself.
un moyen de se dיfendre.
For you.
Tenez.
Now, let us see here.
Voyons un peu.
Barbital. The Mickey slipped.
Du barbital. On l'a droguי.
Drugged him so he couldn't use this.
Pour l'empךcher d'utiliser son arme.
And later around here, a lady's handkerchief.
Et plus tard, ici, le mouchoir d'une femme.
An objet de luxe, handmade.
Un objet de luxe, cousu א la main.
Boom, two hundred francs in Paris.
Facilement 200 francs א Paris.
And she even has an initial, "H."
Il y a mךme une initiale : h.
And our little friend,
Notre petit ami
the pipe cleaner. Another clue.
- le cure-pipe. - Un autre indice.
Yes, a riot of clues dropped most conveniently.
Une foule d'indices commodיment יchappיs.
Yet only one appears, however, to be perhaps genuine.
Pourtant, un seul me semble authentique.
And maybe this ashtray provides
Le cendrier nous fournira
the accidental breadcrumb.
une bribe d'information accidentelle.
A charred fragment of a note.
Un fragment calcinי d'une lettre.
An attempt, perhaps, to burn evidence.
On a peut-ךtre tentי de brler une preuve.
We may borrow your equipment, yes?
Prךtez-nous votre יquipement.
Thank you.
Merci.
Now, I prefer to understand...
Je prיfטre comprendre la raison
why a clue is left rather than what the object is.
de la prיsence d'un indice plutפt que sa nature.
We seek the truth from within, not without.
C'est א l'intיrieur qu'il faut chercher la vיritי.
In this case, however,
Dans ce cas, par contre,
I may welcome a little scientific assistance.
j'ai besoin d'aide scientifique.
You will adjust the flame.
Vous ajusterez la flamme.
It's just another one of those nasty letters.
Encore une lettre de menaces.
You are mistaken, mon ami.
Erreur, mon ami.
This one has a secret to tell.
Celle-ci a un secret א nous rיvיler.
Look.
Regardez.
"As a strong blood is on hand, you will die."
"Sang sur les mains, vous mourrez."
What does this mean?
Qu'est-ce que חa signifie ?
Come with me, Bouc.
Suivez-moi, Bouc.
Let us fill in the gaps.
Nous allons combler les vides.
This was never a beachside puzzle.
ַa n'a jamais יtי une יnigme de vacances.
I know the dead man's real name.
Je connais le vrai nom du dיfunt.
It is not Ratchett, but Cassetti.
Ce n'est pas Ratchett, mais Cassetti.
I know that name.
Je connais ce nom.
Then you will also know the name Armstrong.
Vous connaissez donc aussi le nom Armstrong.
The Armstrong case?
L'affaire Armstrong ?
The story shocked the world.
Cette histoire a choquי le monde.
Two years ago...
Il y a deux ans,
the renowned pilot, Colonel John Armstrong...
le colonel John Armstrong, pilote rיputי,
and his wife, Sonia,
et sa femme Sonia,
woke to find their only child, little Daisy...
ont dיcouvert que Daisy, leur fille unique,
taken from her crib as she slept.
avant יtי enlevיe pendant son sommeil.
Desperate...
Dיsespיrיs,
the Armstrongs paid the ransom.
les Armstrong ont payי la ranחon.
But soon after, Daisy was found murdered by...
Peu aprטs, Daisy a יtי retrouvיe tuיe par...
Ratchett, who was Cassetti.
Ratchett, alias Cassetti.
Sonia Armstrong was with child
Sonia Armstrong יtait enceinte
when she received the news.
quand elle a appris la nouvelle.
The shock sent her into premature labor.
Le choc a dיclenchי des contractions.
Neither she nor her baby survived.
Ni le bיbי ni elle n'ont survיcu.
How do you know this, Poirot?
Comment savez-vous cela, Poirot ?
Because John Armstrong told me so himself.
John Armstrong lui-mךme me l'a racontי.
He wrote to me to ask me for my help.
Il m'a יcrit pour demander mon aide.
By the time I received his letter...
Quand j'ai reחu sa lettre,
it was too late.
il יtait dיjא trop tard.
He was found dead of a gunshot wound.
Il avait יtי trouvי mort par balle.
Self-inflicted.
Un suicide.
"Daisy Armstrong's blood is on your hands.
"Vous avez le sang de Daisy Armstrong sur les mains.
"You will die for it."
"Vous mourrez pour cela."
Indeed, you did.
C'est bien ce qui est arrivי.
Monsieur Poirot? Yes, Michel.
- M. Poirot ? - Oui, Michel.
Mrs. Hubbard wants to speak to you.
Mme Hubbard veut vous parler.
I held her as best as I could.
Je l'ai retenue autant que j'ai pu.
Ah, Mrs. Hubbard, I'm sorry to have kept you.
Mme Hubbard, navrי pour l'attente.
You have a head full of steam and a mouth full of words.
Vous brlez d'envie de me parler.
You're goddamn right, I do. What I have been trying...
En effet. J'essaie de vous dire
to tell you all day.
une chose depuis ce matin.
The murderer was in my compartment last night.
Le meurtrier יtait dans ma cabine hier soir.
I thought I'd be killed. Turns out I might have been...
J'ai craint pour ma vie. Avec raison,
only he got Ratchett instead.
sauf que c'est Ratchett qui y est passי.
I woke up in the dark, and I knew
Rיveillיe en pleine nuit, j'ai su
there was a man in my room.
qu'il y avait un homme tout prטs.
You are certain it was a man?
Vous ךtes certaine que c'יtait un homme ?
I know what it feels like to have a man in my bedroom.
Je le sais quand j'ai un homme dans ma chambre.
I told your conductor, and he wouldn't believe me.
Le chef de train n'a pas voulu me croire.
I said, "Check the communication door
Je lui ai dit de vיrifier la porte entre
"between my room and Ratchett's.
ma chambre et celle de Ratchett.
"He must have left through there."
L'intrus est srement sorti par lא.
Sure enough, it was unbolted.
Elle יtait bel et bien dיverrouillיe.
I know I locked it...
Je sais que je l'ai verrouillיe
after what Ratchett said.
aprטs ce que Ratchett m'a dit.
He made a rather overt overture.
Il m'a fait des avances.
Have you perhaps...
Avez-vous entendu parler
heard of the Armstrong kidnapping?
de l'enlטvement de la petite Armstrong ?
You couldn't avoid it.
Difficile de faire autrement.
Morbid stuff.
Une histoire morbide.
The child's murderer, Cassetti...
L'assassin de l'enfant, Cassetti,
died last night.
est mort la nuit derniטre.
Ratchett was the man.
C'יtait Ratchett.
I told you, I knew he was a rotten one.
Je savais que c'יtait un voyou.
You do believe me...
Me croyez-vous
about the man in my room?
א propos de l'homme dans ma chambre ?
I'm aware you think I'm a silly woman.
Je sais que vous me trouvez ridicule.
But I have proof it's true.
Mais j'en ai la preuve.
It is from the uniform...
ַa vient de l'uniforme
of an Orient Express conductor...
d'un chef de train de l'Orient-Express,
but it might have fallen from Michel's
mais Michel a pu le perdre
when he was in your room.
quand il יtait dans votre chambre.
I'm not missing any.
Je n'ai perdu aucun bouton.
I found it
Je l'ai trouvי au pied du lit, sur l'יdredon,
right where I slept.
lא oש je dormais.
What do you call that?
Que dites-vous de חa ?
I call it evidence. Thank you so much, Mrs. Hubbard.
Que c'est un indice. Merci, Mme Hubbard.
Have you ever been to America?
tes-vous allי en Amיrique ?
Once.
Une fois.
Years ago, briefly.
Briטvement, il y a des annיes.
For what purpose?
Dans quel but ?
To confirm a suspicion. Which was?
- Pour confirmer un soupחon. - Lequel ?
That I wouldn't like it.
Que חa ne me plairait pas.
I was offered a post in Boston.
On m'a offert un poste א Boston.
Saw Boston, went straight back to London.
J'ai vu Boston et je suis rentrי א Londres.
Is that where Ratchett was from?
Ratchett יtait-il de lא-bas ?
Boston? I can't says I know.
- De Boston ? - Je l'ignore.
It wouldn't be proper...
ַa n'aurait pas יtי appropriי
to ask.
de le demander.
Carry on.
Continuez.
I last saw...
J'ai vu M. Ratchett
Mr. Ratchett at nine o'clock.
pour la derniטre fois א 21 h.
I brought his coffee and hung up his clothes.
Je lui ai apportי du cafי et j'ai rangי ses vךtements.
You have a toothache, I think.
On dirait qu'une dent vous fait souffrir.
I've got an extraction booked in London this week.
Je la ferai arracher א Londres cette semaine.
Mr. Ratchett insisted on not putting it off any longer.
M. Ratchett insistait pour que je sois traitי.
He said he was tired of hearing
Il en avait assez d'entendre mes geignements יtouffיs.
This sympathetic Ratchett...
Cet empathique Ratchett
was it his usual practice to drink coffee at night?
avait-il l'habitude de boire du cafי le soir ?
Not at all. But he'd been very agitated lately.
Non, mais il יtait trטs agitי rיcemment.
Said he wanted to stay alert, especially so last night.
Il voulait rester alerte, surtout la nuit derniטre.
He found a letter in his compartment.
Il avait trouvי une lettre dans sa cabine.
Please tell me you didn't do this.
Dites-moi que ce n'est pas de vous.
If I were to leave something unpleasant
Si je laissais un message dיplaisant
on your pillow, sir...
sur votre oreiller, monsieur,
it would not be a letter.
ce ne serait pas une lettre.
Coffee.
Mon cafי.
Surely, such a...
Je doute qu'un valet
proper and precise valet...
aussi consciencieux que vous
would never speak to his master as you did?
parle א son maמtre sur ce ton.
Unless he knew his career was coming to a sudden...
ְ moins qu'il sache que sa carriטre arrivait
end.
א sa fin.
No mere toothache, I think.
Ce n'est pas un simple mal de dent.
The lungs?
Les poumons ?
The thyroid.
La thyroןde.
Spread now to stomach.
Mיtastases א l'estomac.
Same as got my father, five years younger.
Comme pour mon pטre, cinq ans plus jeune.
Months at best.
Quelques mois, sans plus.
"Inoperable, I'm afraid," said the doctor.
"Inopיrable, je le crains", a dit le mיdecin.
And suddenly, I wasn't... afraid.
Du coup, je n'ai plus eu... peur de rien.
I would only do what I wanted from here on.
Je pouvais faire seulement ce qui me plaisait.
I speak my mind now.
Je pouvais ךtre honnךte.
The coffee.
Le cafי.
It appears that his cup was laced with barbital.
Quelqu'un y a glissי du barbital.
You, of course, will tell me
Vous me direz srement que ce n'est pas vous.
Of course I didn't.
Bien sr que ce n'est pas moi.
When and from where
Oש et quand
did you procure the coffee and the cups?
avez-vous ramassי le cafי et les tasses ?
In the kitchen, sir.
Dans la cuisine, monsieur.
I ordered it at dinner to be ready at 9:00, and so it was.
Au souper, j'avais demandי qu'il soit prךt א 21 h.
Anybody could have got a hold of it before me.
N'importe qui aurait pu y toucher avant moi.
Mr. Masterman.
M. Masterman.
I'm sorry about the toothache.
Navrי pour votre mal de dent.
I love the little cakes.
J'adore les petits gגteaux.
So, Miss Pilar Estravados, you are a missionary...
Mlle Pilar Estravados, vous ךtes missionnaire,
but you trained as a nurse
mais vous יtiez infirmiטre avant de changer de mיtier.
I owed it to God.
Je le devais א Dieu.
You owed Him a debt?
Vous aviez une dette envers Lui ?
There were...
J'ai eu...
indulgent times in my life...
Des pיriodes d'indulgence dans ma vie.
when I took more than I gave.
J'ai pris plus que j'ai donnי.
Gerhard Hardman.
Gerhard Hardman.
Professor of engineering.
Professeur de gיnie.
It is science that will win back
C'est la science qui redonnera א l'Allemagne sa fiertי.
- Biniamino Marquez. - Mr. Marquez.
- Biniamino Marquez. - M. Marquez.
Listen, I wanna be clear
Je veux me dיtacher
of any association with the crime...
de toute association avec le crime,
so please ask me anything.
alors allez-y, interrogez-moi.
Anything. I never lie anymore.
Je ne mens plus.
Did you leave your compartment at all last night?
Avez-vous quittי votre cabine hier soir ?
Only once, to get an aspirin.
Une fois, pour aller chercher de l'aspirine.
Mrs. Hubbard offered me something earlier.
Mme Hubbard m'en avait offert.
I declined at first, but when I couldn't rest...
J'ai d'abord refusי, mais incapable de dormir,
I went to ask for it.
je suis allיe lui en demander.
My conference is in Turin.
Ma confיrence est א Turin.
I am the only Austrian to present,
Je dois ךtre le seul confיrencier autrichien,
which means without me...
alors sans moi,
the talks will be substandard.
les exposיs seront mיdiocres.
Then I escaped prison,
Je me suis יvadי de prison et,
and I bribed myself into the US...
entrי aux ֹtats-Unis grגce א un pot-de-vin,
where I swore never to lie or steal again.
j'ai jurי de ne plus voler ni mentir.
You see, my friends, because when people
Quand les gens sont en confiance,
trust you, they buy more.
ils achטtent davantage.
The Italians are cows. The Spaniards, sheep.
Les Italiens sont des vaches. Les Espagnols, des moutons.
The Belgians...
Les Belges...
I come to my room, which I share
Je partage ma chambre
with the unhappy English butler.
avec le valet anglais malheureux.
A fish. He groans a lot.
Il geint beaucoup.
But I'm sure he saw me sleep all night until morning.
Il a d me voir dormir jusqu'au matin.
I should say...
Je dois dire,
in case it is relevant...
au cas oש ce serait pertinent,
there was an embarrassing moment.
qu'il y a eu un moment gךnant.
When I went to see Mrs. Hubbard...
Quand je suis allיe voir Mme Hubbard,
first, I opened the wrong door.
je me suis trompיe de porte.
Oh, sorry.
Oh, pardon.
What time was this?
Quelle heure יtait-il ?
That must have been about...
Il devait ךtre...
Don't be sorry.
Ne vous excusez pas.
...twenty minutes to 11:00.
... 22 h 40.
This is interesting.
C'est intיressant.
As far as it is known,
ְ ce que l'on sache,
you are the last person to see Ratchett alive.
vous ךtes la derniטre א avoir vu Ratchett vivant.
Your business? Automobiles.
- Votre domaine ? - L'automobile.
I have three showrooms.
J'ai trois salles d'exposition.
I come to America with nothing. And now...
Arrivי en Amיrique, je n'avais rien. ְ prיsent...
If what you say is true,
Si c'est vrai, elle me le dira.
Miss Debenham will confirm it.
Mlle Debenham le confirmera.
But it is true.
Mais c'est vrai.
I would not lie.
Je ne mentirais pas.
May it be possible that Miss Debenham
Est-il possible que Mlle Debenham
left your compartment without you noticing?
ait quittי la cabine א votre insu ?
No. I sleep very lightly.
Non. J'ai le sommeil lיger.
The slightest sound and I bolt upright.
Au moindre bruit, je suis debout.
I was surprised once.
On m'a surprise une fois.
Never again.
Plus jamais.
No, I didn't say I was a chauffeur.
Je n'ai pas dit que j'יtais chauffeur.
The photographs that spilled out of your luggage...
Les photos dans vos bagages.
there was a beautiful one
Il y en avait une belle
with a little boy wearing a chauffeur's hat...
d'un petit garחon coiffי d'une casquette,
visiting his papa at work.
visitant son papa au travail.
Who did you chauffeur?
Pour qui יtiez-vous chauffeur ?
Miss Estravados, why do your hands
Mlle Estravados, pourquoi vos mains
have the calluses of a boxer?
ont-elles des rugositיs, comme un boxeur ?
I do my work in dangerous cities...
Je travaille dans des villes dangereuses.
where I cannot be governed by fear.
Je ne peux pas laisser la peur me dominer.
I trained to fight.
J'ai appris א me battre.
But you do not trust your god anymore...
Vous n'avez plus confiance en Dieu
since your surprise?
depuis votre surprise ?
No, in case He is busy.
C'est au cas oש Il serait occupי.
God is always busy.
Dieu est toujours occupי.
It's Masterman.
C'est Masterman.
A man dying is a man with nothing to lose.
Un mourant n'a rien א perdre.
Bravo, Bouc. Except for the problem of Mr. Marquez...
Bien dit, Bouc. Sauf que M. Marquez
who has now confirmed
a maintenant confirmי
that his bunkmate, Masterman...
que son cochambreur, Masterman,
was reading in his bed at the time of death.
lisait au lit au moment de la mort.
If it were easy, I would not be famous. Next.
Je ne serais pas cיlטbre si c'יtait facile. Suivant.
Miss Debenham...
Mlle Debenham,
you do not mind to brace the air?
braver l'air froid ne vous dיrange pas ?
For you, we have the picnic.
Nous avons un piquenique pour vous.
While you made my roommate suffer cramped quarters.
Et pour ma cochambreuse, une voiture יtouffante.
I see.
Je vois.
Choose the best location
Choisir le meilleur endroit
to extract the truth from each suspect.
pour soutirer la vיritי א chacun.
Put her off-balance and me, freeze.
Elle, la dיstabiliser. Moi, me faire geler.
Clever.
Astucieux.
Will you write down your full name
ֹcrivez votre nom complet
and address, please?
et votre adresse, je vous prie.
A pale mauve, by the way.
Mauve pגle, au fait.
Miss Estravados told me you asked
Mlle Estravados a dit que vous aviez
the color of her dressing gown.
demandי la couleur de son peignoir.
"Mary Hermione Debenham."
"Mary Hermione Debenham."
Do you ever go by Hermione?
Vous appelle-t-on parfois Hermione ?
A constant Mary, when I'm not employed as Miss Debenham.
Toujours Mary, ou Mlle Debenham au travail.
Left-handed.
Gauchטre.
Unusual, I know.
Inhabituel, je sais.
You mustn't have your theory fixed
Vous n'avez aucune piste si vous analysez mon יcriture.
What did you think of the dead man?
Que pensiez-vous du dיfunt ?
Uh, I can't say I did think about him.
Euh, je ne pensais pas du tout א lui.
I don't quite see the point of your question.
Je vois mal le but de la question.
Oh, forgive me, mademoiselle, my little originalities.
Pardonnez mes excentricitיs, mademoiselle.
Human nature is perverse in its complexity.
La nature humaine est perverse dans sa complexitי.
To plumb it, it takes the right tools.
Il faut les bons outils pour la percer.
These are toys, not tools, Hercule.
Il s'agit de jouets et non d'outils, Hercule.
I prefer you put them away.
Laissez donc tomber tout חa.
The direct method? Parfait.
La mיthode directe ? Parfait.
You knew the doctor before traveling?
Le mיdecin l'avez-vous connu avant le voyage ?
Dr. Arbuthnot?
Le Dr Arbuthnot ?
No.
Non.
But such instant attraction?
L'attirance a יtי immיdiate ?
We are not in America...
Nous ne sommes pas en Amיrique,
Miss Debenham. There are no laws
Mlle Debenham. Aucune loi n'interdit
against what you may feel.
ce que vous ressentez.
Nor are there laws against silence, of which...
Il n'y a pas non plus de loi contre le silence.
I hold my...
Je prיfטre m'en tenir...
I've never been to America.
Je ne suis jamais allיe en Amיrique.
Perhaps I may ask about some...
J'ai des questions sur quelques
words I overheard?
paroles que j'ai entendues.
You and the stranger, Arbuthnot,
Vous et l'יtranger, Arbuthnot,
are closer than strangers might be.
ךtes plus proches que deux יtrangers moyens.
You said...
Vous avez dit :
"Not now. When we are done. Then no one can touch us."
"Quand ce sera rיglי, rien ne pourra nous toucher."
What did you mean?
De quoi parliez-vous ?
You think I meant murder?
Vous croyez que je parlais de meurtre ?
To a man with a hammer, every problem is a nail.
Pour l'homme au marteau, chaque problטme est un clou.
You live crime.
Vous vivez entourי de crime.
You see evil every day. Not so.
- Le mal est votre quotidien. - Non.
I see enough crime to know
Je vois assez de crimes pour savoir
that the criminal act is the anomaly.
qu'il s'agit d'anomalies.
I believe it takes a fracture of the soul...
Je crois qu'il faut avoir l'גme brisיe
to murder another human being.
pour tuer un de nos semblables.
I ask again, what did you mean?
Je le rיpטte : de quoi parliez-vous ?
As we established...
Nous avons convenu
there are no laws against my silence.
qu'il n'y a pas de loi contre le silence.
Very well.
Trטs bien.
And afterwards, Princess Dragomiroff?
Et aprטs, princesse Dragomiroff ?
After dinner, I came to bed.
Aprטs le souper, je me suis couchיe.
God blessed me with long life,
Dieu m'a offert une longue vie,
but cursed me with a bad back to make it miserable.
mais affligיe d'un dos qui me fait souffrir.
About a quarter to 1:00...
Vers une heure moins quart,
I called for Fräulein Schmidt.
j'ai appelי Frהulein Schmidt.
and read to me for a while.
et m'a fait la lecture un moment.
- Then I sleep. - Mmm-hmm.
Puis, j'ai dormi.
Were you ever acquainted...
Avez-vous dיjא connu
with a family by the name of Armstrong?
une famille du nom d'Armstrong ?
They endured an unspeakable tragedy.
Ils ont souffert une tragיdie innommable.
I was an admirer of Sonia Armstrong's mother...
J'admirais beaucoup la mטre de Sonia Armstrong,
Linda Arden, the actress.
l'actrice Linda Arden.
A once-a-century talent.
Un talent comme on en voit une fois par siטcle.
Miss Arden was to turn to directing.
Mme Arden allait devenir metteuse en scטne.
She would have become the first
Elle aurait יtי la premiטre grande femme de Broadway
were it not for the tragedy.
si ce n'avait יtי de cette tragיdie.
And this Linda Arden, she is dead?
Linda Arden est-elle morte ?
She might as well be.
C'est tout comme.
She no longer leaves her home.
Elle ne sort plus de chez elle.
Daisy was my goddaughter.
Daisy יtait ma filleule.
She was a...
Elle יtait...
I don't see how this relates to our troubles, Detective.
Quel est le lien avec nos ennuis, dיtective ?
The man killed last night, his true name was Cassetti.
L'homme tuי hier soir s'appelait en fait Cassetti.
The man who murdered little Daisy Armstrong.
C'יtait l'assassin de la petite Daisy Armstrong.
I see.
Je vois.
I admit I know this family, and now this man is dead.
J'avoue connaמtre la famille, et cet homme est mort.
The coincidence...
La coןncidence
must seem unbearable.
doit ךtre insupportable.
You may be permitted a coincidence.
Vous avez droit א une coןncidence.
I must now ask a few questions of your Fräulein Schmidt.
J'ai quelques questions א poser א Frהulein Schmidt.
No. There is no need.
C'est inutile.
I can answer to her character.
Je me porte garante d'elle.
Even still, if you will allow.
Tout de mךme, permettez-moi.
Fraulein. Answer please in German.
Frהulein, rיpondez-moi en allemand.
But her Excellency cannot comprehend me.
Mais Son Excellence ne me comprendra pas.
That is the point.
Justement.
This is yours? H for Hildegarde?
Est-ce א vous ? H pour Hildegarde ?
It is too fine for me.
C'est bien trop raffinי pour moi.
This is the truth about last night?
Dit-elle la vיritי א propos d'hier soir ?
As she said. She sent the conductor for me,
Oui. Le chef de train est venu me chercher.
then I returned to bed.
Aprטs, je suis retournיe au lit.
Did you see anyone when you returned?
Avez-vous vu quelqu'un ?
Only the other conductor.
Seulement l'autre chef de train.
"The other conductor."
"L'autre chef de train." Vous parlez de Michel ?
No. A different one than had awoken me.
Non. Pas celui qui m'a rיveillיe.
Please come with me.
Suivez-moi.
Are you sure you did not see him?
Est-ce lui que vous avez vu ?
I'm certain. The other conductor
Non. L'autre chef de train יtait un petit homme barbu.
Fräulein, there is no other conductor.
Frהulein, il n'y a que lui.
I know what I saw.
Je sais ce que j'ai vu.
I remember because his voice was high
Il avait une voix aiguכ et portait le mךme uniforme.
Though, I suspect, missing one button.
Mais il lui manquait un bouton.
Sir, I need your passkey immediately.
Monsieur, prךtez-moi votre passe-partout.
We need to find a uniform and a red kimono.
Nous cherchons un uniforme et un kimono rouge.
Thousands of photographs,
Des milliers de photos, des chaussettes א l'infini,
dressing gowns in every color but red...
des peignoirs de toutes les couleurs sauf rouge,
and still no contraband conductor's uniform.
mais aucun signe d'un faux uniforme.
Have we checked all the passengers' luggage?
On a vיrifiי les bagages de tout le monde ?
All except for the Count
Sauf le comte
and Countess Andrenyi, monsieur.
et la comtesse Andrenyi, monsieur.
It is forbidden to search their suitcases.
Il est interdit de fouiller leurs valises.
They travel under diplomatic visas.
Ils ont des visas de diplomates.
Where else could it be?
Oש pourrait-il bien ךtre ?
There is one last suitcase we have not checked.
Il reste une valise qui n'a pas יtי fouillיe.
The killer is mocking me.
Le tueur se moque de moi.
Good. His first mistake.
Bien. Sa premiטre erreur.
And as the night must follow the day...
Et puisque la nuit doit suivre le jour...
No, it's not mine.
Non, ce n'est pas א moi.
I told you of the conductor. Why would I tell you
Vous aurais-je parlי du chef de train
if it was me? You would not...
- si c'יtait moi ? - Non,
which makes your compartment the ideal choice to hide it.
ce qui fait de votre cabine la cachette idיale.
Voilà, the button.
Voilא, le bouton.
And if a conductor's uniform...
Et avec un uniforme de chef de train,
why not a conductor's passkey?
pourquoi pas un passe-partout aussi ?
Now we know how the killer
Voilא comment le tueur
magically passed through locked doors.
a pu franchir par magie des portes verrouillיes.
Bourbon. MacQueen.
- Du bourbon. - MacQueen.
Now what are we looking for now?
Que cherchons-nous א prיsent ?
500 pounds.
Cinq cents livres.
MacQueen also had a ledger.
MacQueen avait aussi un journal.
All his dealings with Ratchett.
Toutes les transactions de Ratchett.
Where is it, hmm?
Oש est-il ?
Poirot?
Poirot ?
Bouc, keep everyone inside!
Bouc, gardez tout le monde א l'intיrieur !
Please stay where you are.
Veuillez rester lא oש vous ךtes.
Thank you, gentlemen. Thank you.
Merci, messieurs. Merci.
So, it was MacQueen? You have your man?
C'יtait MacQueen ? Vous tenez votre homme ?
How could he?
Comment a-t-il pu ?
I didn't kill him!
Je ne l'ai pas tuי !
You tried to burn Ratchett's accounts...
Vous avez brlי les comptes,
but they are still legible in places.
mais ils restent en partie lisibles.
The maths do not tally...
Les calculs sont inexacts
because you have been stealing from him.
parce que vous le voliez.
It is full of the...
Ils sont pleins de...
- What is the English word? - The chocolat?
Comment dit-on ? Le fard.
Fudge? Fudge!
- Maquillage ? - Maquillage !
It is full of the fudge!
Les comptes sont maquillיs !
You stole from him!
Vous le voliez !
You thought you would be found out.
Vous craigniez de vous faire prendre.
That is why you killed him!
Vous l'avez donc tuי !
Yeah.
Oui.
Yeah, you're damn right I stole from him.
C'est vrai, je le volais.
Thousands.
Je lui ai pris des milliers.
I knew his money wasn't honest.
Je savais que c'יtait de l'argent sale.
What did it matter if I skimmed some off the top?
ַa changeait quoi que je me serve ?
But let me ask you a question.
Mais j'ai une question pour vous.
Why would I slaughter my cash cow?
Pourquoi aurais-je tuי ma vache א lait ?
I didn't do it.
Ce n'est pas moi, le coupable.
- I didn't kill him! - He didn't.
- Je ne l'ai pas tuי ! - C'est vrai.
He didn't.
Ce n'est pas lui, le coupable.
I expect his alibi revolves around me,
J'imagine que son alibi repose sur moi,
drinking till the early hours.
buvant avec lui jusque tard.
Well, it's true.
Eh bien, c'est vrai.
I saw him having whiskey, and remarked
Je l'ai vu boire son whisky et j'ai commentי
on the lesser quality of American liquor.
la qualitי infיrieure de l'alcool amיricain.
He offered me a tipple
Il m'a offert quelques verres pour me faire changer d'avis.
We got to arguing politics. He had some...
On a discutי de politique. Il avait quelques
tomfool opinions on Stalin
opinions ridicules sur Staline
I had to correct. But the man knows his spirits.
א rectifier. Mais l'alcool, il connaמt חa.
A word, please, monsieur.
J'aimerais vous parler, monsieur.
You can confirm you were with him all night?
Vous יtiez donc avec lui toute la soirיe ?
We smoked and spoke till nearly 2:00, yes.
ְ fumer et א bavarder, jusqu'א 2 h ou presque.
Ah, such chums, him with his cigarettes, and you...
Entre amis, lui avec ses cigarettes et vous...
Yes, you are the only man on the train who smokes a pipe.
Le seul homme du train א fumer la pipe.
May I see your pipe and your tobacco, please?
Puis-je voir votre pipe et votre tabac ?
Of course.
Bien sr.
And you, Dr. Arbuthnot,
Et vous, Dr Arbuthnot,
were traveling from India, I believe. Yes?
vous revenez d'Inde, je crois bien ?
You're interviewing me now? Mmm-hmm.
Vous m'interrogez ?
Were you ever in Ratchett's compartment
tes-vous entrי voir Ratchett avant sa mort ?
But this is one of your pipe cleaners, n'est-ce pas?
Mais ce cure-pipe est le vפtre, n'est-ce pas ?
If you found that in the dead man's cabin, look elsewhere.
Si vous l'avez trouvי prטs du dיfunt, cherchez encore.
I am a doctor, sir.
Je suis mיdecin, monsieur.
I heal people. I do not hurt them.
Je soigne les gens. Je ne les tue pas.
About this, see, you must have worked
Vous avez d travailler
very hard to become a doctor.
trטs fort pour devenir mיdecin.
Not many of your race are allowed the opportunity.
Peu de votre race ont cette occasion.
Middlesex Medical College permits one per class.
Un par annיe au collטge mיdical Middlesex.
I had the honor in '24.
J'ai eu cet honneur en 1924.
I was a sniper in my tour.
J'יtais tireur d'יlite durant mon service.
A sharpshooter.
Un des meilleurs.
Saved more than a few officers.
J'ai sauvי bon nombre d'officiers.
The more grateful,
Les plus reconnaissants
recognized a fair mind with a steady hand...
ont su voir mon souci de rigueur
and supported my education.
et m'ont soutenu dans ma formation.
I take their generosity as a debt.
Je leur dois beaucoup.
Did you know a Colonel Armstrong?
Connaissiez-vous un colonel Armstrong ?
Might have known two or three Armstrongs.
Je crois avoir connu deux ou trois Armstrong.
Tommy in the 60th... Selby Armstrong...
Tommy du 60e... Selby Armstrong...
No, I meant Colonel John Armstrong.
Je parle du colonel John Armstrong.
He had an American wife,
Il a יpousי une Amיricaine.
and his child was kidnapped and killed.
Leur fille a יtי enlevיe et tuיe.
Never came across the fellow.
Je ne l'ai pas connu.
When did you first meet Miss Debenham?
Quand avez-vous rencontrי Mlle Debenham ?
We met when we shared the railway convoy car
Dans le wagon que nous partagions
from Kirkuk to Nissibin.
entre Kirkouk et Nissibin.
She claims otherwise,
Elle affirme autre chose,
and she has made herself problematically suspicious.
ce qui la rend malheureusement suspecte.
Mary is a lady.
Mary est une dame.
Leave her out of this. I can vouch for her character.
Laissez-la. Je me porte garant d'elle.
As you vouched for MacQueen's time?
Et de l'emploi du temps de MacQueen ?
You are lucky. The good doctor insists
Vous avez de la chance. Le mיdecin affirme
he did not let you out of his sight.
qu'il ne vous a pas quittי des yeux.
See? There. Couldn't have done it.
Vous voyez ? ַa ne peut pas ךtre moi.
Yes, you could.
Oui, חa le pourrait.
Ratchett took a sleeping draught each evening.
Ratchett prenait un somnifטre chaque soir.
You could add barbital, easily access that drug.
Vous auriez facilement pu y ajouter du barbital,
Do the same with one of the doctor's many drinks...
faire de mךme avec l'un des verres du mיdecin
and the chance to kill him is clear.
et saisir l'occasion de le tuer.
Why would I do any of that?
Pourquoi aurais-je fait חa ?
We have established your motive.
Vous aviez un mobile.
Perhaps I will suggest a different one.
J'en ai un autre א suggיrer.
A different reason, a more personal reason.
Une raison diffיrente, plus personnelle.
"A lawyer by education, not by disposition."
"Avocat de formation, pas de tempיrament."
Why did you pursue the law, I wonder?
Pourquoi avoir יtudiי le droit ?
Was it to appease a much loved,
ֹtait-ce pour contenter un pטre aimי,
but demanding father...
mais exigeant,
one who himself had made a great success
qui avait lui-mךme connu du succטs
in the same field...
dans cette profession
and then lost his position?
avant de perdre son poste ?
There was a renowned MacQueen, was there not?
Il y a eu un MacQueen rיputי, n'est-ce pas ?
The district attorney for the state of New Jersey...
Procureur de l'ֹtat du New Jersey,
responsible for the prosecution
responsable de la poursuite dans l'affaire Armstrong.
They didn't have a suspect.
Il n'y avait aucun suspect.
My dad was pressured to go after
Mon pטre a יtי sommי de s'en prendre
this poor French woman...
א une pauvre Franחaise,
a maid with a weak alibi, Susanne.
Susanne, une domestique dont l'alibi יtait faible.
He hung his whole case on her.
Toutes les accusations reposaient sur elle.
She killed herself.
Elle s'est suicidיe.
She was innocent.
Elle יtait innocente.
By the time the evidence lead to Cassetti,
Les preuves ont fini par incriminer Cassetti,
oh, he was long gone.
mais il avait filי depuis longtemps.
They tore my old man apart.
Mon pטre a יtי anיanti.
I couldn't do anything for him.
Je ne pouvais rien pour lui.
And yet you claim
Vous affirmez pourtant ignorer que Ratchett יtait Cassetti.
No, no.
Je l'ignorais.
But you found him.
Mais vous l'avez trouvי.
No.
Non.
You found him.
Vous l'avez trouvי.
You bled him dry... No.
- Vous l'avez lessivי... - Non.
in order to settle your father's debts,
... pour rembourser les dettes de votre pטre
and then finally, to settle the score.
et vous venger enfin.
No, no, no.
Non, non, non.
No. It wasn't...
Non. Ce n'יtait pas...
It wasn't like that. It's not the way...
ַa ne s'est pas passי ainsi. Ce n'יtait pas...
Someone kicked in the door...
- On a enfoncי la porte... - Docteur !
covered my face.
... et on m'a couvert le visage.
All right, this needs to come out now.
Il faut l'enlever tout de suite.
I want my bag. Of course.
- Je veux ma trousse. - Bien sr.
It's in my compartment.
Elle est dans ma cabine.
There will be no fingerprints.
Pas d'empreintes digitales.
The killer was disposing of the murder weapon.
Le tueur jetait l'arme du crime.
The killer didn't hit a lung or artery.
Le tueur n'a pas touchי de poumon ni d'artטre.
She's lucky to be alive.
Elle a de la chance d'ךtre en vie.
You all are.
Comme vous tous.
Yeah, some genius!
Vous parlez d'un gיnie !
Why haven't you solved this case?
Pourquoi n'avez-vous pas rיsolu l'affaire ?
You must give the man some time.
Donnez-lui du temps.
Yeah, well...
Oui, bien...
I can't give that much more. I don't have any blood left.
J'ai dיjא beaucoup donnי. Je suis exsangue.
Yeah.
Oui.
Accosting Mr. MacQueen,
Vous interrogiez M. MacQueen
and the real killer is right here.
alors que le vrai tueur est ici.
One of you people.
C'est l'un de vous.
I don't know who you are. I said nothing.
J'ignore qui vous ךtes. Je n'ai rien dit.
Please, leave me alone.
Laissez-moi tranquille.
Play something.
Musique.
My friends, the tracks will be cleared by morning.
Le chemin de fer sera dיblayי demain matin.
Please, return to your rooms.
Retournez א vos chambres.
I'm sleeping here...
Je dormirai ici,
where everyone can see me and I can see everyone.
oש tout le monde me voit et je vois tout le monde.
You should all do the same. Conserve heat.
Faites tous cela pour rester au chaud.
Remain in the open, safely in view, until morning.
Restez en sretי, bien en vue, jusqu'au matin.
A killer will never hesitate to kill again.
Un tueur n'hיsite pas א rיcidiver.
I will convey the same message to the Andrenyis...
Je vais passer le message aux Andrenyi,
diplomatic immunity or not.
immunitי diplomatique ou non.
If I may, I will look at your passports.
J'aimerais voir vos passeports.
You know that I must talk with her.
Je dois lui parler, vous savez.
By the way, there is a grease spot on your wife's name.
Le nom de votre femme est tachי.
You might want to look at that.
Vous devriez y voir.
Elena is not well.
Elena se porte mal.
If you do not permit me, your reluctance
Si vous persistez, votre rיticence
will be noted to the Yugoslav Police...
sera notיe par la police yougoslave.
and I have no doubt that they will arrest both you and...
Vous serez certainement arrךtיs tous les...
How dare you!
- Comment osez-vous ? - Chיri !
Darling.
Chיri.
You are funny-looking, monsieur Poirot.
Vous avez une drפle d'allure, M. Poirot.
Are all detectives so funny-looking?
Est-ce le cas pour tous les dיtectives ?
I am sorry to wake you, Madame la Comtesse.
Pardon de vous rיveiller, madame la comtesse.
I am always awake at night.
Je passe mes nuits debout.
In the day, I sleep.
Je dors durant le jour.
Some fear darkness, but I cannot stand the light.
Certains craignent le noir. Moi, c'est la lumiטre.
You are always under the influence of...
Vous ךtes toujours sous l'influence du...
Barbital.
Barbital.
Barbital, barbital.
Le barbital, le barbital.
I take oceans of it.
J'en prends des tonnes.
Oh, there's no use in a lie, love.
Oh, inutile de mentir, mon amour.
He can see right through us.
On ne peut rien lui cacher.
I cannot go outside without it.
Sans חa, je ne peux pas sortir.
I cannot sleep without it.
Je ne peux pas dormir.
I take it against my fears.
J'en prends pour lutter contre mes peurs.
What are you afraid of?
De quoi avez-vous peur ?
Everything.
De tout.
Your passport has your maiden name as Goldenberg.
Je vois que votre nom de jeune fille est Goldenberg.
Jewish, yes?
Vous ךtes juive ?
Not so Jewish. My middle name isn't Maria.
Pas tant que חa. Mon deuxiטme prיnom est Maria.
And you are a dancer like your husband?
Vous dansez, comme votre mari ?
No, not like my husband.
Non, pas comme mon mari.
Corps de ballet.
Le corps de ballet.
He is touched by angels.
Il a יtי bיni par les anges.
I have been shoved by passion
Moi, la passion
and hard work to become adequate.
et l'acharnement m'ont rendue potable.
Excuse me, I must lie down again.
Excusez-moi, je dois me recoucher.
Is this your only dressing gown?
Est-ce votre seul peignoir ?
No, I have another. Corn-colored chiffon.
Non, j'en ai un autre en chiffon couleur maןs.
I like speaking to detectives.
J'aime parler aux dיtectives.
You never know what they're going to ask you next.
On ne sait jamais ce qu'ils vont demander.
I'm particularly good at capitals.
Je connais trטs bien les capitales.
My governess was a stickler for geography.
Ma gouvernante insistait sur la gיographie.
Are you satisfied?
tes-vous satisfait ?
I am always satisfied when I uncover a liar.
Dיmasquer un menteur me satisfait toujours.
Madame, your name is not Elena. It is Helena.
Madame, votre nom est Helena, pas Elena.
Despite your clumsy attempts
Malgrי vos essais maladroits
to change it here and on your luggage.
pour le changer ici et sur vos bagages.
My husband heard
Mon mari a entendu qu'on avait trouvי un indice,
a handkerchief embroidered with an "H,"
un mouchoir portant l'initiale h.
and didn't want my "H" involved.
Je ne voulais pas que mon h soit mךlי א חa.
So we changed it. The luggage and the passport.
On a donc modifiי le passeport et les bagages.
It's no crime to want to be distant from trouble.
Ce n'est pas un crime de fuir les ennuis.
Yet, here is trouble.
Pourtant, les ennuis vous suivent.
A curious detail
Un יtrange dיtail concernant
about the Armstrong tragedy at the heart of this case...
la tragיdie Armstrong au cur de cette affaire,
is how many people were wounded by it.
c'est le nombre de personnes qui ont יtי blessיes.
The younger sister.
La sur cadette.
The actress mother...
La mטre actrice,
stage name, Linda Arden.
Linda Arden de son nom d'artiste.
I suppose she, too, was of Jewish ancestry...
Elle devait ךtre aussi d'origine juive.
as who is most likely to take a stage name?
Qui d'autre adopte un nom d'artiste ?
Is it too far to suggest...
Serait-ce aller trop loin que de suggיrer
her original name was Goldenberg?
que son vrai nom יtait Goldenberg ?
Especially when we find a young woman,
Surtout lorsque nous trouvons une jeune femme
the same age...
du mךme גge
as her surviving daughter...
que la fille qui lui reste,
living in a world of fear?
vivant dans un monde de peur ?
The sister of Sonia Armstrong.
La sur de Sonia Armstrong.
Get out!
Sortez !
I hear noises and I run. Just in time, yes?
Le bruit m'a fait accourir. Juste א temps, non ?
You must now believe the count and countess are the killers.
Vous devez croire le comte et la comtesse coupables.
The count is protective.
Le comte est protecteur.
The countess would no sooner kill a bedroom spider.
La comtesse ne ferait de mal א personne.
And you may desist with this charade.
Vous pouvez cesser votre cirque.
You are neither an Austrian, nor a German, nor a professor.
Vous n'ךtes ni autrichien, ni allemand, ni professeur.
But a good imitation.
Mais vous ךtes bon imitateur.
Was it based on someone you know?
Vous ךtes-vous inspirי d'une connaissance ?
A local butcher where I grew up was a Kraut.
Le boucher du quartier quand j'יtais petit, un boche.
Good man, great accent.
Un homme bon qui avait un bel accent.
What was it?
Comment l'avez-vous su ?
You said "Tur-in..."
Votre prononciation de "Turin"
the emphasis on the wrong syllable
avec l'accent sur la mauvaise syllabe
for a proud and proper Teuton.
pour un authentique fier Teuton.
"Tu-reen."
"Tu-rine."
You are one sharp knife, I give you that.
Vous ךtes drפlement futי, je dois l'admettre.
Herr Professor Gerhard Hardman...
Le professeur Gerhard Hardman,
is my cover.
c'est ma fausse identitי.
I'm sorry about the colored folks cracks.
Excusez mes commentaires sur les gens de couleur.
Hell, I'm half a Heeb myself.
Je suis moi-mךme א moitiי juif.
Cyrus Bethman Hardman.
Cyrus Bethman Hardman.
You are a Pinkerton detective?
Un dיtective de l'agence Pinkerton ?
30 years.
Depuis 30 ans.
I was in Stamboul, coming back from a job,
Je terminais un contrat א Istanbul
when the office cabled.
quand j'ai reחu un tיlיgramme.
Ratchett asked for a man to tail him,
Ratchett voulait qu'on le surveille,
offering triple time.
trois fois le salaire habituel.
Lucky me being nearby.
J'ai eu de la chance d'ךtre dans le coin.
He told me to look out
Il m'a dit de guetter
for a small, dark man with a high voice.
un petit homme basanי א la voix aiguכ.
I watched that hall...
J'ai surveillי le couloir
all night through a crack in my door.
toute la nuit par une fente dans ma porte.
Any thug...
Le malfaiteur, qui qu'il soit,
had to go by me first.
devait passer devant moi.
I'll take my oath on it.
Je le jure.
And would you also take your oath...
Jureriez-vous aussi
on your thirty years as a Pinkerton Detective...
que vous avez 30 ans de service pour Pinkerton
or would you lie to me again...
ou me mentiriez-vous encore
and deny that you were, in fact, a policeman first?
en niant que vous avez d'abord יtי policier ?
Your gun, the checkered grip, the blue finish...
Votre arme. Sa crosse, sa finition bleutיe...
produced for the Police Positive edition.
Typique des modטles remis א la police.
1927 issue.
ֹdition 1927.
It appears there are no end to the lies
Il n'y a pas de fin aux mensonges
manufactured just for me.
qu'on invente juste pour moi.
You can leave your gun as you go, Professor.
Laissez votre arme en sortant, professeur.
From the position of his cabin...
D'aprטs la position de sa cabine,
it would have been impossible to miss.
il n'aurait pas pu rater le tueur.
Unless Ratchett's door was open...
ְ moins que la porte de Ratchett ait יtי ouverte...
as Pilar Estravados claims she opened it.
Et Pilar Estravados affirme l'avoir ouverte.
In which case, someone could have been...
Dans ce cas, quelqu'un aurait pu
masked from his view.
יchapper א son regard.
This is an abominable crime...
C'est un crime abominable,
and I am stuck, ma Katherine.
et je n'y vois pas clair, ma Katherine.
I cannot find the crack in the wall.
Je ne trouve pas la fissure dans le mur.
Why does one of them elude me?
Qui arrive א me duper ?
I have always been...
J'ai toujours יtי
so sure.
si certain.
Too sure.
Trop certain.
But now, I am very humble.
Je me sens א prיsent trטs humble
And I say, like a little child...
et je dis, comme un petit enfant,
I do not know.
que je ne sais rien.
I am afraid, ma Katherine.
J'ai peur, ma Katherine.
My apologies, ladies and gentlemen.
Mes excuses, mesdames et messieurs.
It is not safe on board
Ce n'est pas sr א bord
whilst the engine is put back on the tracks.
pendant qu'on replace le train.
We are to wait in the tunnel. Thank you.
Il faut attendre dans le tunnel. Merci.
Where are they taking the dogs?
Oש emmטnent-ils les chiens ?
They'll be happy.
Ils seront bien.
That's not right.
ַa ne se fait pas.
Just to stretch their legs, it's good.
C'est juste pour se dיgourdir un peu.
No, that's not right.
Non, חa ne se fait pas.
It's freezing!
On gטle !
Are we stuck?
On est coincיs ?
You asked for me?
Vous m'avez demandיe ?
Another interrogation?
Un autre interrogatoire ?
Oh, no. I enjoy your company.
Oh, non. J'aime votre compagnie.
Merci, Bouc.
Merci, Bouc.
Uh, please.
Je vous en prie.
I have a list of ten questions I am no nearer to answering...
J'ai dix questions toujours sans rיponses
and the train is about to leave.
alors que le train va partir.
You have a clear mind...
Vous avez l'esprit alerte.
and I thought that you might produce an insight. Please.
J'ai pensי que vous auriez peut-ךtre une idיe.
"The handkerchief. The pipe cleaner.
"Le mouchoir. Le cure-pipe.
"The scarlet kimono. The uniform.
"Le kimono rouge. L'uniforme.
"The time on the watch.
"L'heure sur la montre.
"Was he murdered then? Earlier or later?
"A-t-il יtי tuי א ce moment, avant ou aprטs ?
"By one person or more?
"Par une personne ou plusieurs ?
"Which of them?"
"Laquelle ou lesquelles ?"
Sorry, I can't help you.
Je regrette, je ne peux pas vous aider.
Perhaps there is an eleventh question
Il y en a peut-ךtre une onziטme
you don't know to ask yet...
que vous n'avez pas encore posיe
that will give you the answer to the rest.
et qui vous fournira la rיponse aux autres.
Perhaps.
Peut-ךtre.
I could point an easy finger at the, uh, Countess Andrenyi.
Je pourrais accuser la comtesse Andrenyi.
I discovered she was Sonia Armstrong's sister.
J'ai dיcouvert qu'elle יtait la sur de Sonia Armstrong.
Are you certain? Yes.
- En ךtes-vous certain ? - Oui.
I suspect she may perhaps be innocent.
Je crois qu'elle est peut-ךtre innocente.
Perhaps.
Peut-ךtre.
But so many people have lied to me
Mais tant de personnes m'ont menti
on this train and do not seem to mind.
avec insouciance dans ce train.
You yourself did so effortlessly.
Vous l'avez fait sans effort.
Me?
Moi ?
You told me you had never been to America.
Vous dites n'avoir jamais visitי l'Amיrique.
You also concealed the fact
Vous m'avez aussi cachי qu'au moment de la tragיdie,
you were living in the Armstrong household...
vous viviez chez les Armstrong
as governess to their daughter.
en tant que gouvernante de leur fille.
And you know this.
Vous le savez.
I have my living to get.
Je dois gagner ma vie.
A girl detained in connection to a murder case...
Une jeune femme arrךtיe pour meurtre...
no decent class family would engage me.
Aucune bonne famille ne m'engagerait.
Miss Debenham, you planned Ratchett's murder.
Mlle Debenham, vous avez planifiי le meurtre.
And then you sent for the countess to witness it.
Vous avez fait venir la comtesse comme tיmoin.
If she saw him dead,
Si elle le voyait mort,
the Helena you knew might return.
la Helena d'autrefois pourrait revivre.
You waited for your roommate to sleep, but she did not.
Votre cochambreuse n'avait pas sommeil.
You drugged her.
Vous l'avez droguיe.
But the barbital only gave her a headache.
Le barbital lui a donnי mal א la tךte.
She begged for an aspirin when the train stopped,
Elle a demandי une aspirine lors d'un arrךt,
when the conductor was on the station...
quand le chef de train יtait sorti
when the coast was clear at last...
et que la voie יtait libre
when you were allowed to enter
pour que vous entriez en secret
Ratchett's compartment, unseen.
dans la cabine de Ratchett.
You loved Daisy Armstrong. You killed Cassetti.
Vous aimiez Daisy Armstrong. Vous avez tuי Cassetti.
Cassetti was a pig.
Cassetti יtait un porc.
He deserved to die.
Il mיritait de mourir.
She didn't kill him.
Elle ne l'a pas tuי.
I did.
C'יtait moi.
Mary, go.
Pars, Mary.
I can't let you take the blame...
Je ne te laisserai pas prendre le blגme
for what I did alone.
pour ce que j'ai fait seul.
Mary, please, go.
Mary, je t'en prie, pars.
John Armstrong was my best friend,
John Armstrong יtait mon meilleur ami,
my commander.
mon commandant.
He believed in me.
Il croyait en moi.
He sent me to medical school, gave me a future.
Il a payי mes יtudes, m'a offert un avenir.
Cassetti destroyed him.
Cassetti l'a anיanti.
In grief, I found Mary.
Dans ma douleur, j'ai trouvי Mary.
Then I found Ratchett.
Puis, j'ai trouvי Ratchett.
Our plan was to reveal him to the police,
Notre plan יtait de le dיnoncer א la police,
that's what you heard.
c'est ce que vous avez entendu.
But when I saw his face...
Mais en voyant son visage,
I knew he didn't deserve a trial.
j'ai su qu'il ne mיritait pas un procטs.
So, you drugged MacQueen.
Vous avez droguי MacQueen.
You changed the time on the watch...
Vous avez changי l'heure sur la montre
so that you could lie about the time of death.
pour mentir א propos de l'heure du dיcטs.
I couldn't let Mary be accused.
Je ne pouvais pas laisser Mary ךtre accusיe.
Or MacQueen.
Ni MacQueen.
My sins are mine to pay for, alone.
Je paierai seul pour mes pיchיs.
I'm a soldier.
Je suis un soldat.
A soldier kills to protect.
Un soldat tue pour protיger.
And now, Mr. Poirot,
ְ prיsent, M. Poirot, je dois me protיger de vous.
Why aren't you dead yet?
Pourquoi n'ךtes-vous pas mort ?
Gentlemen, stop!
Messieurs, arrךtez !
Sir, we need to get all the passengers
Il faut faire remonter tous les passagers
back on the train.
dans le train.
You will retire...
Vous devez
away from the train...
vous יloigner du train
until I tell you to return.
jusqu'א ce que je vous dise de revenir.
You tell your lies...
Vous racontez vos mensonges
and you think no one will know.
et vous croyez que personne ne s'en rendra compte.
But there are two people who will know.
Mais deux personnes s'en rendront compte.
Yes, two people.
Oui, deux personnes.
Your God...
Votre Dieu
and Hercule Poirot.
et Hercule Poirot.
It is time to solve this case.
L'heure est venue de rיsoudre cette affaire.
Dr. Arbuthnot asked me why I was not yet dead.
Le Dr Arbuthnot m'a demandי pourquoi je n'יtais pas mort.
He knew, of course, the answer.
Il connaissait la rיponse, bien sr.
A sharpshooter who does not kill at close range?
Un tireur d'יlite qui rate sa cible א bout portant ?
Your shot was not a mistake. It was a surgery.
Votre tir avait une prיcision chirurgicale.
You could not kill me because you are no killer.
Vous ne pouviez pas me tuer, car vous n'ךtes pas un tueur.
None of you are killers.
Aucun de vous n'est un tueur.
And yet, someone must be.
Pourtant, quelqu'un a tuי.
There are two possible solutions to this crime.
Il y a deux solutions possibles א ce crime.
One difficult, because it fits with most
Une qui concorde avec la majoritי
but not all of the facts...
des faits, mais pas tous,
and one more...
et une autre,
complex.
plus complexe.
The first solution.
Voyons la premiטre.
Ratchett had enemies.
Ratchett avait des ennemis.
A rogue Mafioso steals onto the train at Vinkovci...
Un mafieux monte dans le train א Vinkovci
as MacQueen and Arbuthnot take the air.
pendant que MacQueen et Arbuthnot prennent l'air.
Equipped with a uniform
ֹquipי d'un uniforme
and a passkey, he stabs Ratchett.
et d'un passe-partout, il poignarde Ratchett.
He leaves through Mrs. Hubbard's compartment,
Il sort par la cabine de Mme Hubbard
and makes his escape.
et s'יchappe.
No.
Non.
No, no, no. It doesn't work.
Non, חa n'a pas de sens.
Why hide the uniform, hmm?
Pourquoi cacher l'uniforme ?
Who drugs Ratchett?
Qui a droguי Ratchett ?
Or stabs Mrs. Hubbard?
Ou poignardי Mme Hubbard ?
Damn it, man!
Bon sang !
So I ask, who stands to benefit?
Qui ce crime avantage-t-il ?
This crime is the murdering of a murderer.
Ce crime, c'est le meurtre d'un meurtrier.
The benefit is, perhaps...
L'avantage est peut-ךtre
to the spirit, an ease of suffering.
de mettre fin aux souffrances de l'esprit.
To quiet a shouting voice
De faire taire une voix intיrieure
in the head that prevents sleep.
qui hurle et nuit au sommeil.
There is a murderer among us.
Un meurtrier se trouve parmi nous.
So...
Donc...
We have Dr. Arbuthnot,
On a le Dr Arbuthnot,
a dedicated, grateful friend to Colonel Armstrong.
ami dיvouי et reconnaissant du colonel Armstrong.
He meets and finds solace
Il trouve du rיconfort auprטs
in the company of the governess, Mary Debenham...
de la gouvernante, Mary Debenham,
who is almost like a mother to the little girl.
une deuxiטme mטre pour la fillette.
And so close to Mrs. Armstrong's young sister,
Et trטs proche de la jeune sur de Mme Armstrong,
Helena Goldenberg...
Helena Goldenberg,
married to a powerful man
יpouse d'un homme puissant
no stranger to rage and violence.
qui n'est pas יtranger א la rage et א la violence.
We travel also with Daisy's godmother...
Nous voyageons aussi avec la marraine de Daisy,
to whom belongs...
א qui appartient
the monogrammed handkerchief
le mouchoir brodי trouvי sur les lieux du crime.
The letter "H" in the Russian alphabet,
La lettre h, dans l'alphabet russe,
of course, pronounced "N."
se prononce n.
Natalia Dragomiroff.
Natalia Dragomiroff.
And her devoted maid with a chef's eye?
Et la domestique dיvouיe qui a l'il d'un chef ?
Who was she before her current employ?
Qui יtait-elle auparavant ?
Might I suggest the Armstrongs' cook?
La cuisiniטre des Armstrong, peut-ךtre ?
But we are not yet done.
Mais ce n'est pas terminי.
The nurse in charge of Daisy...
L'infirmiטre qui prenait soin de Daisy,
her newfound religious zeal
prise d'une ferveur religieuse issue
born of guilt at allowing her charge...
de sa culpabilitי d'avoir laissי la petite
to be abducted. It was you, was it not...
se faire enlever. Vous יtiez lא, n'est-ce pas,
in her room the night when
dans la chambre, la nuit
Ratchett came in through the window?
oש Ratchett est entrי par la fenךtre ?
Did you have a glass of wine too many
Aviez-vous bu un verre de vin de trop
with your supper that night?
au souper ce soir-lא ?
Have you blamed yourself ever since...
Vous blגmez-vous depuis
for not being alert to stop him?
d'avoir יtי trop endormie pour l'arrךter ?
She knew nothing but kindness...
Elle ne connaissait que la douceur
and love, until...
et l'amour, jusqu'א ce que...
until I...
Jusqu'א ce que je...
No need to divine with me, sir.
Nul besoin de deviner avec moi.
I was Colonel Armstrong's batman in the war.
J'ai servi le colonel Armstrong pendant la guerre.
And afterwards, his valet in New York.
Aprטs, j'ai יtי son valet א New York.
As fine a man as God ever made.
Un des grands hommes que Dieu ait mis sur terre.
Would his chauffeur agree?
Son chauffeur serait-il d'accord ?
Was it a bank loan, secured by Armstrong,
Serait-ce un prךt obtenu par Armstrong
allows him to build his automobile empire?
qui l'a aidי א bגtir son empire automobile ?
He's indebted for life. Who else can we count?
Il avait une dette יnorme. Qui d'autre ?
What of the Pinkerton detective,
Le dיtective de Pinkerton, autrefois policier affectי
assigned to the Armstrong case?
א l'affaire Armstrong ?
And he becomes attached to someone,
Il s'יtait attachי א quelqu'un,
for there is another, uncelebrated victim.
une victime mיconnue.
You fell in love with the maid
Vous יtiez amoureux de la domestique
before she was falsely accused.
avant qu'elle soit faussement accusיe.
You quit the police when you witnessed...
Vous avez dיmissionnי de la police,
the travesty ofjustice...
tיmoin d'un simulacre de justice
when MacQueen's father insisted on her arrest.
lorsque le pטre de MacQueen l'a fait arrךter.
When she took her own life.
Elle s'est ensuite enlevי la vie.
No! No, no!
Non ! Non !
Susanne was so gentle.
Susanne יtait si charmante.
And she fell for me.
Et elle avait des sentiments pour moi,
Old and already getting grey.
dיjא vieux et grisonnant.
I told her she could do better...
Je lui disais qu'elle pouvait faire mieux,
but there she was...
mais elle יtait lא,
on time for every date.
א l'heure pour chaque rendez-vous.
Why else is a train...
Pourquoi un train
so full in the dead of winter? Why the inconsistent wounds?
bondי en plein hiver ? Les blessures inconstantes ?
Why the abundance of evidence? Why...?
Pourquoi les multiples indices ? Pourquoi...
Why the conductor?
Pourquoi le chef de train ?
Pierre Michel of Avignon...
Pierre Michel, d'Avignon,
who lost his sister...
qui a perdu sa sur,
the accused maid...
la domestique accusיe.
Susanne Michel.
Susanne Michel.
Only one soul can claim to have lost
Une seule גme peut affirmer avoir perdu
more than any of you.
plus que vous tous.
The tragic Linda Arden...
La pauvre Linda Arden,
mother of Sonia...
mטre de Sonia,
grandmother of Daisy.
grand-mטre de Daisy.
Retired from the stage...
Elle s'est retirיe du thיגtre
but for one final performance.
pour un dernier rפle.
You're an awfully clever man.
Vous ךtes terriblement brillant.
A murder should have one victim.
Un meurtre devrait n'avoir qu'une victime.
When Ratchett kills Daisy Armstrong...
Quand Ratchett a tuי Daisy Armstrong,
a dozen lives are broken, deformed, ended.
il a dיtruit une dizaine de vies.
They demand justice!
Elles exigent que justice soit faite !
Of all these wounded souls, we must finally answer...
Ces גmes brisיes doivent enfin rיpondre.
who among them is a killer?
Qui d'entre elles est capable de tuer ?
Who takes up the knife? The answer is...
Qui prendra le couteau ? La rיponse est
No single one of you could have done it.
qu'aucun de vous ne pouvait le faire seul.
Nor any pair.
Ni א deux.
It can only have been done...
Cela ne pouvait ךtre fait
by all of you.
que par vous tous.
Together.
Ensemble.
Even when the avalanche changes everything...
Mךme lorsque l'avalanche a tout changי,
as does the detective, plans must change.
ainsi que le dיtective. Les plans ont d changer.
The kimono, the uniform.
Le kimono, l'uniforme.
A remarkable improvisation,
Une remarquable improvisation.
the doctor who knows how to wound without killing.
Le mיdecin qui sait blesser sans tuer.
Each has their part to play.
Chacun a son rפle א jouer.
Do it.
Faites-le.
It was my plan.
C'יtait mon plan.
I recruited them.
Je les ai recrutיs.
I had Hardman track down Cassetti.
Hardman a retrouvי Cassetti pour moi.
I sent MacQueen to work for him,
J'ai envoyי MacQueen travailler pour lui,
and then Masterman.
puis Masterman.
MacQueen could arrange
MacQueen pouvait planifier
he travel on the day that Michel was on duty.
un voyage lorsque Michel יtait en service.
Mr. Ratchett?
M. Ratchett ?
And so it is done.
Donc, ce fut fait.
For the death of the innocent.
Pour la mort d'une innocente.
Revenge.
La vengeance.
No one should hang for this but me.
Moi seule devrais ךtre pendue pour cela.
It was my plan!
C'יtait mon plan !
There's no life left in me anymore.
Ma vie est terminיe.
They have a chance now.
Ils ont encore une chance de vivre la leur.
Helena, I pray...
Helena, j'espטre,
has a chance.
a une chance.
They can...
Ils peuvent
go live...
vivre leur vie,
find some joy...
trouver la joie,
somewhere.
quelque part.
Let it end with me.
Que cela finisse avec moi.
They're not killers.
Ce ne sont pas des tueurs.
They're good people.
Ce sont de bonnes personnes.
They can be good again.
Ils peuvent redevenir bons.
There was right, there was wrong.
Il y avait le bien, il y avait le mal.
Now there is you.
ְ prיsent, il y a vous.
I cannot judge this.
Je ne peux pas juger cela.
You must decide.
Vous devez dיcider.
You wish to go free
Si vous souhaitez ךtre libres, impunis pour votre crime,
then you must only commit one more.
vous devrez en commettre un dernier.
I will not stop you.
Je ne vous en empךcherai pas.
You can't let them kill you.
Vous ne pouvez pas les laisser vous tuer.
You give my body to the lake,
Jetez mon corps dans le lac
and you walk away innocent at the station.
et quittez la gare en innocents.
You must silence me.
Vous devez me faire taire.
Bouc can lie.
Bouc peut mentir.
I cannot.
Pas moi.
Do it! One of you!
Faites-le ! Un d'entre vous !
Don't.
Non.
I already died with Daisy.
Je suis dיjא morte en mךme temps que Daisy.
No!
Non !
You said your role was to find justice.
Vous disiez que votre rפle יtait de trouver la justice.
What is justice here?
Quelle justice y a-t-il ici ?
Sometimes, the law of man is not enough.
La loi de l'homme ne suffit pas toujours.
Where does conscience lie?
Oש est votre conscience ?
Buried with Daisy.
Enterrיe auprטs de Daisy.
My dear Colonel Armstrong.
Cher colonel Armstrong,
Finally, I can answer your letter...
je peux enfin rיpondre א votre lettre
at least with the thoughts in my head
avec la conviction dans l'esprit
and the feeling in my heart...
et le sentiment dans le cur
that somewhere, you can hear me.
qu'oש que vous soyez, vous pouvez m'entendre.
I have now discovered
J'ai fini par dיcouvrir
the truth of the case, and it is...
la vיritי sur l'affaire, et elle est
profoundly disturbing.
profondיment troublante.
I have seen the fracture of the human soul.
J'ai vu la fracture de l'גme humaine.
So many broken lives, so much pain and anger...
Tant de vies brisיes, de douleur et de colטre,
giving way to the poison of deep grief...
faisant place au poison du dיsespoir
until one crime became many.
jusqu'א ce qu'un crime devienne multiple.
I have always wanted to believe
J'ai toujours voulu croire
that man is rational and civilized.
que l'homme est rationnel et civilisי.
My very existence depends upon this hope...
Mon existence mךme dיpend de cette croyance
upon order and method and the little gray cells.
en l'ordre, en la mיthode et en l'intellect.
But now, perhaps, I am asked...
Mais א prיsent, on me demande peut-ךtre
to listen, instead...
d'יcouter plutפt
to my heart.
mon cur.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Mesdames et messieurs,
I have understood in this case that the scales of justice...
dans cette affaire, la balance de la justice
cannot always be evenly weighed.
ne saurait peser יquitablement les choses.
And I must learn, for once...
Je dois apprendre, pour une fois,
to live with the imbalance.
א vivre avec le dיsיquilibre.
There are no killers here.
Il n'y a pas de tueur ici.
Only people who deserve a chance to heal.
Seulement des gens qui mיritent de guיrir.
The police have accepted
La police a acceptי ma premiטre hypothטse,
the lone assassin who made his escape.
celle de l'assassin qui aurait rיussi א fuir.
I will leave the train here to conclude formalities.
Je descends du train ici pour terminer les formalitיs.
You are all free to go.
Vous ךtes libres de partir.
And may you find your peace with this.
Je vous souhaite de trouver la paix.
May we all.
Je nous le souhaite א tous.
Hello.
Bonjour.
I'm looking for a Mr. Poirot.
Je cherche M. Poirot.
He's needed on a very urgent matter.
On le demande dans une affaire urgente.
The, uh, Kassner case again?
Encore l'affaire Kassner ?
No, sir, far worse.
Non, monsieur. Bien pire.
I have to take him to Egypt straight away.
Je dois vite l'escorter jusqu'en ֹgypte.
There's been a murder, sir, right on the bloody Nile.
Il y a eu un meurtre sur le Nil.
Are you the detective?
C'est vous, le dיtective ?
Yes.
Oui.
I am the detective.
C'est moi, le dיtective.
Could you please straighten your tie?
Pouvez-vous redresser votre cravate ?
I will see you at the car.
Je vous rejoins א la voiture.
Here you are, sir.
Voilא, monsieur.